<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BD Newspaper Scraper</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EhsanulHaqueSiam/BDNewsPaperScraper</link>
    <description>Latest news from Bangladeshi newspapers (200 articles)</description>
    <language>en-bd</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:57:17 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>BDNewsPaperScraper RSS Generator</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka rejects Indian advice on election process: Touhid</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31619</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31619</guid>
      <description>Foreign Adviser Md Touhid Hossain today said Dhaka does not seek advice from India on Bangladesh’s election process, calling New Delhi’s recent comments unacceptable while reaffirming the interim government’s commitment to holding a free, fair and credible national election. “We do not want advice from our neighbours on how elections in Bangladesh should be held,” he said while responding to journalists’ questions at the Foreign Ministry here this afternoon. The adviser added that India had rema...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31619">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia wants Dhaka-Delhi to reduce tension</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31696</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31696</guid>
      <description>Russian Ambassador Alexander Grigoryevich Khozin today urged Bangladesh and India to reduce domestic tensions between the neighbouring countries. Speaking at a press briefing at the Embassy of the Russian Federation in Dhaka, the Ambassador underscored the importance of de-escalating tensions with India &amp;quot;the sooner the better,&amp;quot; while stressing that Russia does not interfere in bilateral relations between the two countries. He said bilateral relations between neighbouring countries should be guid...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31696">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid postal voting system to set global example: CEC</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31699</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31699</guid>
      <description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) A M M Nasir Uddin has said Bangladesh’s newly introduced ‘hybrid postal voting’ is expected to become a model for countries around the world. He made the remarks while talking to journalists after inspecting postal ballot operations at the Tejgaon Mail Processing Centre in the capital this afternoon. “We are hopeful that this hybrid model (online registration combine manual counting of postal ballots) will emerge as a global example,” the CEC said. He said that ...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31699">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamas official says Egypt to host Palestinian conference on Gaza future</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=30349</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=30349</guid>
      <description>A senior Hamas official said Saturday that Egypt would organise a conference for Palestinian factions to decide on the post-war future of the Gaza Strip, after the group accepted to release hostages under a US ceasefire plan. Egypt will host an &amp;quot;intra-Palestinian dialogue on Palestinian unity and the future of Gaza, including the administration of the Gaza Strip&amp;quot;, the official told AFP. Hamas on Friday said it would release hostages held in Gaza under US President Donald Trump&amp;#x27;s ceasefire plan, ...</description>
      <category>International</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=30349">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highest security for Tarique Rahman&amp;#x27;s homecoming on Dec 25: Home Adviser</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31693</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31693</guid>
      <description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has said the highest level of security will be ensured for the homecoming of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on December 25. &amp;quot;Maximum security measures have already been taken to ensure the safe arrival of Tarique Rahman in the country,&amp;quot; he said. The Home Adviser made the remarks today while briefing reporters after the 18th meeting of the Advisory Council Committee on Law and Order and on securit...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31693">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saimon Overseas Cleared of Money Laundering Allegations</title>
      <link>https://www.arthosuchak.com/archives/940917/saimon-overseas-limited-cleared-of-money-laundering-allegations/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.arthosuchak.com/archives/940917/saimon-overseas-limited-cleared-of-money-laundering-allegations/</guid>
      <description>Saimon Overseas Limited has been officially cleared of allegations of money laundering after an investigation by the Ministry of Civil Aviation and Tourism found the claims to be false, unfounded, and misleading. According to informed sources, a vested interest group allegedly carried out a planned smear campaign against the company following its strong stance against long-standing irregularities in the air ticketing market. These irregularities include anonymous group bookings and prolonged sea...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://www.arthosuchak.com/archives/940917/saimon-overseas-limited-cleared-of-money-laundering-allegations/">Artho Suchak</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:42:18 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique calls CA Yunus, expresses gratitude</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53463</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53463</guid>
      <description>Immediately after landing in Dhaka, BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman made a phone call to Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus from the airport to express his gratitude. A video of the phone conversation has been shared on Tarique Rahman’s official Facebook page. In the video, Tarique Rahman is heard saying: &amp;quot;On behalf of myself and my family, I want to thank you. You have made various arrangements, especially for my security. And we are… thank you so much… thank you so much for all the arrangements...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53463">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold wave continues, affecting normal life in northern region</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53498</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53498</guid>
      <description>Although the minimum temperatures remained mostly unchanged and maximum temperatures increased slightly, the mild cold wave blowing over the northern region continued affecting the normal life for the third consecutive day on Thursday. The sky remained partly cloudy and misty till noon with cold winds blowing from the west and northwest. The sufferings of the poor people living in the riverbank and char areas of the Brahmaputra basin remained deplorable today as it has been for the past few days...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53498">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>England dominate as Australia bowled out for 152 in 4th Ashes Test</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/26/53524</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/26/53524</guid>
      <description>England tore through the Australian batting line-up to bowl the hosts out for just 152 on day one of the fourth Ashes Test at the Melbourne Cricket Ground, taking complete control on a green, bowler-friendly track, reports AFP. Skipper Ben Stokes won the toss and sent Australia in under overcast skies. Openers Travis Head and Jake Weatherald fell for 12 and 10, while Marnus Labuschagne managed only six, as Gus Atkinson and Josh Tongue exploited early movement. Steve Smith tried to stabilize the ...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/26/53524">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique’s motorcade off to Gulshan</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53497</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53497</guid>
      <description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman left for his Gulshan residence after visiting his mother, former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia, who is undergoing treatment at Evercare Hospital in Bashundhara. The bus carrying him left Evercare Hospital at around 7:30 pm on Thursday (December 25). Earlier, Tarique Rahman visited the hospital at around 5:45 pm. When the bus carrying him reached the hospital gate, he got off and walked inside. Top party leaders accompanied him at the time. Tarique Rahman’s w...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53497">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salah scores goal as Egypt rally to win against Zimbabwe</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/23/53334</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/23/53334</guid>
      <description>Mohamed Salah snatched a dramatic stoppage-time winner as Egypt came from behind to beat Zimbabwe 2-1 in their first fixture at the Africa Cup of Nations (AFCON) finals in Morocco on Monday. Egypt’s captain, starting his first game after four successive matches ⁠on the bench at Liverpool, fired home a left-footed effort in the 91st minute to earn the seven-time champions a ​late victory after Zimbabwe had stunned them by going ahead in the first half, reports AL Jazeera. Egypt laid an early ‍sie...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/23/53334">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajshahi hand captaincy to Shanto ahead of BPL</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/22/53270</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/22/53270</guid>
      <description>Najmul Hossain Shanto will lead Rajshahi Warriors in the upcoming Bangladesh Premier League, with the franchise confirming his captaincy on Monday, reports the Daily Sun. The Rajshahi Warriors’ media group shared the information. Rajshahi have placed their trust in the national Test captain, who has previously led Bangladesh in all three formats, despite having several experienced options in the side. The squad features players like Mushfiqur Rahim and Akbar Ali. However, the franchise opted to ...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/22/53270">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Awesome’ Australia dominate to clinch Ashes as England left hurting</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53224</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53224</guid>
      <description>Australia captain Pat Cummins described the moment as “pretty awesome” on Sunday after his dominant side wrapped up the Ashes with victory in the third Test in Adelaide, sealing the series in just 11 days of play despite a defiant final-day stand from England’s tail, reports AFP. Chasing a record 435 to win, England’s last four wickets added a stubborn 145 runs before they were finally dismissed for 352, handing Australia an 82-run victory and ensuring the famous urn remained in Australian hands...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53224">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>England beaten to lose another Ashes in Australia</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53206</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53206</guid>
      <description>England&amp;#x27;s Bazball project is in tatters as yet another Ashes in Australia was lost in three Tests, reports BBC. The visiting team were defeated by 82 runs on the fifth day of the third Test in Adelaide to go 3-0 down and extend a winless run in this country to 18 matches. Australia were delayed by a 40-minute rain shower, England pair Jamie Smith and Will Jacks, and a hamstring injury to spinner Nathan Lyon. Smith had 60 when he miscued Mitchell Starc. Jacks battled past lunch for his 47 then ed...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53206">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jumar–Urmi fall in final, secure historic silver</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53182</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53182</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh’s mixed doubles pair Al Amin Jumar and Urmi Akter made history by reaching the final of an international badminton tournament for the first time, winning the silver medal at the Yonex-Sunrise Bangladesh International Challenge 2025, reports the Daily Sun. In the mixed doubles final, the Bangladeshi duo faced Malaysia’s Datu Anif and Clarissa San. Jumar and Urmi fought hard in the opening game but were unable to sustain the pressure in the later stages, eventually losing the match 27–2...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53182">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mbappé matches Ronaldo’s Real Madrid record with 59 goals in a calendar year</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53191</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53191</guid>
      <description>Kylian Mbappé equaled a long-standing Real Madrid record on Saturday after scoring his 59th goal of 2025, matching Cristiano Ronaldo’s mark for the most goals in a single year for the club, reports UNB. The French forward sealed Madrid’s 2-0 victory over Sevilla with a late penalty, converting from the spot four minutes from time in the team’s final match of the year. The goal came just in time, as the milestone appeared to be slipping away. Celebrating his 27th birthday, Mbappé reached the same...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53191">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustafizur trumps Taskin to lead Dubai to win in ILT20</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53180</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53180</guid>
      <description>On a day when two Bangladesh pace spearhead faced off in International League T20 (ILT20) in Dubai, Mustafizur Rahman prevailed to lead his side Dubai Capitals to victory, ruining the valiant effort of his compatriot and new ball partner Taskin Ahmed, reports BSS. Mustafizur’s 2-13 became more valuable in his Dubai’s 63-run victory over Sharjah Warriors, who saw Taskin battle lonely for them. Taskin grabbed 3-40 to be the pick of the bowler for Sharjah but despite his superb performance, Dubai p...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53180">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPL tickets for Sylhet phase on sale from Sunday, prices start at Tk200</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53173</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53173</guid>
      <description>Tickets for the Sylhet phase of the 12th edition of the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) will go on sale from Sunday, reports the Daily Sun. The reports confirmed this update, citing Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) media release. The BPL is set to get underway on Friday at the Sylhet International Cricket Stadium, marking the start of another highly anticipated season of the country’s premier T20 tournament. According to a media release, the ticketing process will be conducted entirely online, wit...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53173">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gill misses out on India&amp;#x27;s T20 World Cup squad</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53166</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53166</guid>
      <description>Defending champions and co-hosts India have named their squad for the ICC Men’s T20 World Cup 2026, set to begin on February 7. The hosts enter the tournament aiming to clinch a record third title, ICC reports. Suryakumar Yadav is set to lead India in his first-ever ICC tournament as captain, with Axar Patel named as his deputy in the absence of star batter Shubman Gill, who was dropped after lean performances upon his return to the T20I setup in September. Along with Gill, Jitesh Sharma, who ha...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53166">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajshahi first to begin BPL preparations, but in national kit</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53142</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53142</guid>
      <description>Rajshahi Warriors became the first franchise to begin preparations for the upcoming Bangladesh Premier League, holding their opening practice session on Saturday at the Mirpur Academy Ground. The session took an unusual yet eye-catching turn as the players initially trained wearing Bangladesh national team practice kits instead of their franchise colours. The sight caused brief confusion among onlookers before it was clarified that the Rajshahi Warriors’ official kits had yet to arrive at the ve...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53142">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardiola dismisses Manchester City exit talk ahead of West Ham clash</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53118</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53118</guid>
      <description>Manchester City boss Pep Guardiola dismissed speculation over his future at the club, insisting contract talks are not on the agenda despite rumours he could leave at the end of the season, but added his side were not yet good enough to win the title. While Guardiola&amp;#x27;s team, who host lowly West Ham United on Saturday, could overtake Arsenal for top spot in the Premier League this weekend, the Spaniard&amp;#x27;s job status was the hot topic at his pre-game press conference on Friday. &amp;quot;I always get asked ...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53118">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jumar–Urmi create history by reaching mixed doubles final</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53117</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53117</guid>
      <description>Al Amin Jumar and Urmi Akter continued to deliver good news for Bangladesh, lighting up the night of the weekend just as they had done in the morning. The pair created history in Bangladeshi badminton by reaching the final of the mixed doubles event at the Yonex-Sunrise Bangladesh International Challenge, reports the Daily Sun. Earlier in the day, Jumar and Urmi had already secured at least a bronze medal, but by nightfall, they went one step further, ensuring a place in the final. This marks th...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53117">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan end Bangladesh’s dream with dominant eight-wicket win</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53115</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53115</guid>
      <description>Pakistan Under-19 brought an end to Bangladesh’s quest for a third consecutive title with a commanding eight-wicket victory in the rain-affected semifinal of the U-19 Asia Cup at The Sevens Stadium in Dubai on Friday. Asked to bat first in the curtailed 27-over contest, Bangladesh struggled from the outset and were bowled out for 121 with three balls remaining. The innings never gathered momentum after opener Rifat Beg fell for 14 off 16 balls with 24 runs on the board. Fellow opener and in-form...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53115">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morocco beat Jordan 3-2 after extra time to clinch Arab Cup</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53103</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53103</guid>
      <description>Morocco defeated Jordan 3-2 after extra time to claim the Arab Cup on Thursday, reports Reuters. Abderrazzaq Hamed Allah scored two goals following a stunning long-range strike from Oussama Tannane. Morocco opened the scoring after four minutes when Tannane&amp;#x27;s audacious shot from the centre circle caught advancing goalkeeper Yazeed Abulaila off guard. Jordan, set to make their World Cup debut in 2026, hit back with a second-half double from Ali Olwan&amp;#x27;s header and penalty in the 48th and 68th minu...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53103">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘It was just a misunderstanding’</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53494</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53494</guid>
      <description>Former Bangladesh captain Khaled Mahmud Sujon has played down his dramatic walkout from Noakhali Express’s training session, calling the episode “just a misunderstanding” ahead of the Bangladesh Premier League, reports the Daily Sun. Sujon left the Sylhet International Cricket Stadium on Thursday, initially saying he would not continue in the BPL after becoming frustrated with training arrangements and equipment shortages. “It’s just a misunderstanding. It maybe happened in the heat of the momen...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53494">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shanto prioritises Rajshahi impact with T20 World Cup in sight</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53475</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53475</guid>
      <description>Najmul Hossain Shanto has made no secret of his priorities as he prepares to lead Rajshahi, with the T20 World Cup firmly in his sights, reports the Daily Sun. The Bangladesh batter said team success comes before personal milestones, stressing that consistent performances in the domestic arena could open the door to bigger opportunities. &amp;quot;I think first of all the Rajshahi team is more important to me than individual achievements,&amp;quot; Shanto said, adding that his focus is on making a regular impact,...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53475">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chattogram Royals owner asks BCB to take over franchise</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53444</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53444</guid>
      <description>Chattogram Royals owner Kayum Rashed has asked the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) to take over the operations of the franchise for the remainder of the Bangladesh Premier League season, BPL Governing Council member secretary Iftekhar Rahman Mithu told Daily Sun on Thursday. Kayum submitted a written request to the BCB, citing difficulties in continuing to run the team under the current circumstances, reports Daily Sun. “We have just received the letter. We will sit with the players and discuss t...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53444">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smith returns as Australia prepare an all-pace attack for Boxing Day test</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53466</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53466</guid>
      <description>Steve Smith returns to action in the Boxing Day test against England as Australia opted to include four fast bowlers in their 12-man squad, with spinner Todd Murphy, who was brought into the fold to replace Nathan Lyon, not finding a spot. Fast bowler Jhye Richardson, who has not played in the longest format since 2021, has been brought back after fine domestic form on his return from shoulder surgery. Brendan Doggett who played in the first two tests, and Michael Neser, who was part of the pink...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53466">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bashar, Nafees and Babul appointed as BCB takes charge of Royals</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53467</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53467</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has appointed former national captain Habibul Bashar as mentor, Mizanur Rahman Babul as head coach and Nafees Iqbal as team manager of the Chattogram Royals after agreeing to take over the franchise’s operations for the remainder of the Bangladesh Premier League season. The appointments follow franchise owner Kayum Rashed’s request to the BCB to assume control of the team, citing difficulties in continuing to run the side under the prevailing circumstances. BCB off...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53467">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP to launch cleaning drive at July 36 Expressway (300-feet) tomorrow morning | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/345111</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/345111</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 25, 2025 (BSS) - Dhaka Metropolitan North unit of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) will conduct a voluntary clean-up drive tomorrow morning to remove waste generated following the massive public gathering held to mark the &amp;#x27;historic homecoming&amp;#x27; of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman. BNP Media Cell Convener Professor Dr. Moudud Hossain Alamgir Pavel disclosed the information to the media today. The cleaning operation will cover the July 36 Expressway (300-feet road), Airpor...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/345111">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:12 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Assistant for Home Affairs Khuda Baksh resigns | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/344956</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/344956</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 24, 2025 (BSS) - Chief Adviser&amp;#x27;s Special Assistant for Home Affairs Md Khuda Baksh Chowdhury has resigned from his post. The Cabinet Division issued a notification on Wednesday night, saying that the President has already accepted the resignation. &amp;quot;The resignation of Mr Khuda Baksh Chowdhury, the Special Assistant entrusted with executive authority with the rank of State Minister at the Ministry of Home Affairs of the interim government of the People&amp;#x27;s Republic of Banglades...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/344956">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman thanks countrymen for warm reception | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/345108</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/345108</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 25, 2025 (BSS) - BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman today expressed his sincere thanks and gratitude to the people of the country for the warm reception accorded to him upon his return home from London after long 17 years. A press release issued today said that following his arrival in the country from London, a massive gathering of people was seen stretching from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport to the expressway popularly known as the “300 Feet Road”. The historic a...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/345108">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Day today | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/344954</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/344954</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 25, 2025 (BSS) - Christmas Day, marking the birth anniversary of Jesus Christ, a Jewish preacher and religious leader of the first century, will be observed across the country on Thursday. Christian community in Bangladesh, like elsewhere in the world, will celebrate the day with religious fervour and festivity. Special prayers will be offered at churches, which will be illuminated for the occasion, while makeshift Christmas trees will be set up at homes, churches and missi...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/344954">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:07 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People&amp;#x27;s life, culture key to China-Bangladesh media exchange: Chinese envoy | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/344959</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/344959</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 24, 2025 (BSS) - Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen said that media exchange plays a vital role in understanding the civilization and culture of both countries. &amp;quot;Media exchange allows us to learn closely from each other. The foundation of China-Bangladesh media exchange is the life and culture of our peoples. This provides a strong base for building a relationship of justice between the two countries,&amp;quot; he said. The envoy made the remarks at a function titled &amp;#x27;Golden S...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/344959">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:05 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flight carrying Tarique Rahman lands at Dhaka airport</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286145/flight-carrying-tarique-rahman-lands-at-dhaka-airport</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286145/flight-carrying-tarique-rahman-lands-at-dhaka-airport</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chairman Tarique Rahman returned home from London on Thursday with his wife and daughter after his 17-year exile in London. A flight of Biman Bangladesh Airlines carrying them landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport via Sylhet in Dhaka at 11:40am. Earlier, the flight made a stopover at Sylhet&amp;#x27;s Osmani International Airport at about 9:58am.</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286145/flight-carrying-tarique-rahman-lands-at-dhaka-airport">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique calls chief adviser after landing at airport, expresses gratitude for security arrangements</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286149/tarique-calls-chief-adviser-after-landing-at-airport-expresses-gratitude-for-security-arrangements</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286149/tarique-calls-chief-adviser-after-landing-at-airport-expresses-gratitude-for-security-arrangements</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chair Tarique Rahman on Thursday expressed his gratitude to interim government chief adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus for the arrangements made, particularly for his security, on the occasion of his return from London. Soon after landing at the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka, Tarique Rahman made a phone call to the chief adviser from the airport lounge. A video of the conversation was later shared in Tarique’s verified Facebook page with the c...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286149/tarique-calls-chief-adviser-after-landing-at-airport-expresses-gratitude-for-security-arrangements">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only 27.24pc can influence govt decisions: final report</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286242/only-2724pc-can-influence-govt-decisions-final-report</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286242/only-2724pc-can-influence-govt-decisions-final-report</guid>
      <description>Only 27.24 per cent of citizens say they can influence government decisions at any level, according to the final report on the Citizen Perception Survey 2025. The figure, however, drops to 21.99 per cent when it comes specifically to political influence, said the report released by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics at a ceremony at the BBS auditorium in the capital Dhaka on Wednesday. The preliminary report on the survey was released in June. While the findings suggest a widespread sense of di...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286242/only-2724pc-can-influence-govt-decisions-final-report">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bulletproof bus arrives at airport ahead of Tarique Rahman’s return</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286144/bulletproof-bus-arrives-at-airport-ahead-of-tarique-rahmans-return</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286144/bulletproof-bus-arrives-at-airport-ahead-of-tarique-rahmans-return</guid>
      <description>A bulletproof bus arrived at the CIP gate of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Thursday morning amid tight security ahead of the return of Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chairman Tarique Rahman. The specially prepared bus, painted in red and green, bears large portraits of BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia, BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman and party founder Ziaur Rahman. It also displays slogans highlighting democracy and political struggle. The vehicle’s windows are reinforced, and sec...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286144/bulletproof-bus-arrives-at-airport-ahead-of-tarique-rahmans-return">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Youth beaten after being tied to electric pole in Chapainawabganj</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286241/youth-beaten-after-being-tied-to-electric-pole-in-chapainawabganj</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286241/youth-beaten-after-being-tied-to-electric-pole-in-chapainawabganj</guid>
      <description>A young man was beaten and stabbed to injuries after being tied to an electric pole at Shibganj upazila in Chapainawabganj on Wednesday evening, allegedly due to an internal feud. The incident took place at about 7:00pm in the Umorpur Ghat area of Shyampur union. The injured was Abu Sufian Siju, 25, son of Rabiul Islam of Shyampur–Bajitpur village under the upazila. According to the police and local residents, a group of local youth tied Siju to an electric pole and stabbed him with sharp weapon...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286241/youth-beaten-after-being-tied-to-electric-pole-in-chapainawabganj">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crude bomb explodes at Malibagh</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286239/crude-bomb-explodes-at-malibagh</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286239/crude-bomb-explodes-at-malibagh</guid>
      <description>A crude bomb was exploded near Malibagh intersection in the capital Dhaka on Thursday, a day after a youth was killed in a crude bomb explosion at Moghbazar on Wednesday. A case has been filed in connection with the murder of the youth, the police said. At Malibagh, the crude bomb was exploded at about 12:00pm, according to the Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s traffic division. No casualties were reported in the incident. Meanwhile, a firecracker-like object exploded next to the garbage depot at Mali...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286239/crude-bomb-explodes-at-malibagh">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People’s life, culture key to China-Bangladesh media exchange: Chinese envoy</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/286240/peoples-life-culture-key-to-china-bangladesh-media-exchange-chinese-envoy</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/286240/peoples-life-culture-key-to-china-bangladesh-media-exchange-chinese-envoy</guid>
      <description>Chinese ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen has said that media exchange plays a vital role in understanding the civilisation and culture of both countries. ‘Media exchange allows us to learn closely from each other. The foundation of China-Bangladesh media exchange is the life and culture of our peoples. This provides a strong base for building a relationship of justice between the two countries,’ he said. The envoy made the remarks at a function titled Golden Silk Road Bangladesh Media Award held...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/286240/peoples-life-culture-key-to-china-bangladesh-media-exchange-chinese-envoy">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP activists crowding 300 Feet Road, adjacent places to welcome Tarique</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286143/bnp-activists-crowding-300-feet-road-adjacent-places-to-welcome-tarique</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286143/bnp-activists-crowding-300-feet-road-adjacent-places-to-welcome-tarique</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party leaders and activists started crowding the 300 Feet Road since Thursday morning to welcome its acting chairman Tarique Rahman’s homecoming after 17 years. Leaders and activists were joining the rally since Morning holding placards, photos of Tarique Rahman, fastoons and wearing T-shirts and caps. Kazi Khairuzzaman Shipon, BNP Bagherhat district vice-president, said that he reached Dhaka city two days ago and was staying at a hotel for attending the event. ‘We are her...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286143/bnp-activists-crowding-300-feet-road-adjacent-places-to-welcome-tarique">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nation ready to welcome Tarique Rahman in fascist free Bangladesh: Salahuddin</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286141/nation-ready-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-in-fascist-free-bangladesh-salahuddin</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286141/nation-ready-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-in-fascist-free-bangladesh-salahuddin</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed has said that the nation is ready to accord a grand reception to the party’s acting chairman Tarique Rahman in fascist free Bangladesh. ‘The fascist regime was toppled by a student-people uprising last year. We are very happy and pleased that the nation will welcome BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman in a fascist free Bangladesh,’ he said while briefing journalists in front of the VIP gate of the Hazrat Shahjalal Airport in ...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286141/nation-ready-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-in-fascist-free-bangladesh-salahuddin">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tight security at airport ahead of return of Tarique Rahman</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286142/tight-security-at-airport-ahead-of-return-of-tarique-rahman</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286142/tight-security-at-airport-ahead-of-return-of-tarique-rahman</guid>
      <description>Strict security measures have been put in place at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport ahead of the return of Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chairman Tarique Rahman. Several layers of security have been deployed around the VVIP terminal, with personnel from the army, BGB, air force, police and RAB on duty. RAB dog squads are conducting searches, while a special army unit has also been stationed in the area. In addition, the personal security force of the BNP chairperson and acting chairm...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286142/tight-security-at-airport-ahead-of-return-of-tarique-rahman">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique returns home today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286115/tarique-returns-home-today</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286115/tarique-returns-home-today</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chairman Tarique Rahman is set to return to Dhaka on Thursday after more than 17 years in exile in the United Kingdom, marking a moment of major political significance. The homecoming has generated widespread anticipation nationwide, with supporters preparing to welcome him. The BNP has taken wide-ranging preparations, which party leaders say mirror both the significance of the moment and the sheer scale of public anticipation it has generated. They expressed ...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286115/tarique-returns-home-today">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCP seeks revision of nomination submission, withdrawal deadlines</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286119/ncp-seeks-revision-of-nomination-submission-withdrawal-deadlines</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286119/ncp-seeks-revision-of-nomination-submission-withdrawal-deadlines</guid>
      <description>The National Citizen Party on Wednesday expressed concern about the Election Commission’s capacity for holding the national polls on February 12 next year. The party urged the commission to reconsider the dates for submission of nomination papers and withdrawal of candidature, keeping the voting date unchanged. Speaking after a meeting between an NCP delegation and chief election commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin at the commission headquarters in Dhaka, NCP chief coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary said t...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286119/ncp-seeks-revision-of-nomination-submission-withdrawal-deadlines">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP names 10 more candidates, with nine for allies</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286057/bnp-names-10-more-candidates-with-nine-for-allies</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286057/bnp-names-10-more-candidates-with-nine-for-allies</guid>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party on Wednesday announced candidates for 10 more constituencies, sharing nine of the seats with its movement partners, for the upcoming Jatiya Sangsad elections scheduled for February 12 next year. BNP secretary general Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir announced the names of the 10 candidates at a press conference at the party’s chairperson’s office in the capital’s Gulshan area. Of the 10 candidates, Liberal Democratic Party secretary general Redwan Ahmed, who joined th...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286057/bnp-names-10-more-candidates-with-nine-for-allies">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NDF sets candidates for 122 seats</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286032/ndf-sets-candidates-for-122-seats</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286032/ndf-sets-candidates-for-122-seats</guid>
      <description>The newly-formed National Democratic Front, led by Jatiya Party factions, announced the names of the candidates for 122 seats for the upcoming Jatiya Sangsad elections scheduled for February 12. The executive chairman of a JP faction, Mujibul Haque Chunnu, announced the names of aspirant candidates at a press conference at a city hotel on Tuesday. JP faction chairman Anisul Islam Mahmud, secretary general ABM Ruhul Amin Hawlader, Jatiya Party-JP chairman Anwar Hossain Manju and others spoke at t...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286032/ndf-sets-candidates-for-122-seats">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TARIQUE RETURN: Railway to run special trains, HSIA prohibits visitor entry from evening</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285982/tarique-return-railway-to-run-special-trains-hsia-prohibits-visitor-entry-from-evening</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285982/tarique-return-railway-to-run-special-trains-hsia-prohibits-visitor-entry-from-evening</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Railway is scheduled to start running special trains from today to carry Bangladesh Nationalist Party leaders and activists on the occasion of the party’s leader ’s homecoming tomorrow. Also, Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport authorities prohibited all visitors except designated passengers from entering its area for 24 hours starting from 6:00pm today citing special operational and security reasons. Biman Bangladesh Airlines authorities in a press also also requested the airport-...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285982/tarique-return-railway-to-run-special-trains-hsia-prohibits-visitor-entry-from-evening">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parties pledge democratic country thru reforms</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286026/parties-pledge-democratic-country-thru-reforms</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286026/parties-pledge-democratic-country-thru-reforms</guid>
      <description>Leaders of major political parties on Tuesday expressed grave concern, saying that the recent incidents of violence were casting uncertainty over the forthcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad election. They also outlined their respective visions for democratic reform, economic recovery and governance in post-uprising Bangladesh. The leaders at a dialogue also pledged to build a new Bangladesh through necessary reforms and obliterating fascism, and by means of leading the country to achieve economic freedo...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286026/parties-pledge-democratic-country-thru-reforms">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCP likely to join Jamaat-led alliance</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286213/ncp-likely-to-join-jamaat-led-alliance</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286213/ncp-likely-to-join-jamaat-led-alliance</guid>
      <description>The National Citizen Party, formed by student and youth organisers of the July uprising in February this year, is likely to join the Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami-led alliance ahead of the next general election and the national referendum. The NCP is, however, in confusion about its involvement with the recently formed Ganatantrik Sanskar Jote, an NCP-led alliance launched on December 7. The components of the alliance are the NCP, the Bangladesh Rashtra Sanskar Andolan and the Amar Bangladesh Party...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286213/ncp-likely-to-join-jamaat-led-alliance">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP cedes 4 seats to Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285963/bnp-cedes-4-seats-to-jamiat-ulema-e-islam</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285963/bnp-cedes-4-seats-to-jamiat-ulema-e-islam</guid>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party allotted four Jatiya Sangsad constituencies to the Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam Bangladesh as part of an electoral understanding ahead of the 13th JS elections. As a result of the agreement, BNP electoral symbol ‘sheaf of paddy’ will not be used in these constituencies. Instead, voters were urged to cast their votes for the candidates contesting with the ‘date palm tree’ symbol. BNP secretary general Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir made the announcement at a press conference...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285963/bnp-cedes-4-seats-to-jamiat-ulema-e-islam">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique returns home to rolling reception</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286210/tarique-returns-home-to-rolling-reception</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286210/tarique-returns-home-to-rolling-reception</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chair Tarique Rahman returned to the country on Thursday after ending 17 years in forced exile in the United Kingdom, marking his homecoming with a historic reception attended by over 10 lakh people. Tarique arrived at the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport at around 11:40am on a Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight from London. He was accompanied by his wife Zubaida Rahman, their daughter Zaima Rahman, and the family’s pet cat Zeebu. Extensive security measur...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286210/tarique-returns-home-to-rolling-reception">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique seeks peace, unity on homecoming</title>
      <link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-seeks-peace-unity-on-homecoming</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-seeks-peace-unity-on-homecoming</guid>
      <description>Published : Updated : Share this news On a euphoric homecoming after precious 17 years in forced political exile, BNP leader Tarique Rahman promises political bonhomie in the divisive polity and calls for rebuilding Bangladesh as safe abode for all. At a mammoth reception rally on return home Thursday amid an ambiance of post-uprising unrest, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) acting chairman urged citizens to preserve peace and public order &amp;quot;by any means&amp;quot;, calling for unity and restraint. S...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-seeks-peace-unity-on-homecoming">The Financial Express</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From elders to teenagers, diverse masses throng to welcome Tarique Rahman home</title>
      <link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/from-elders-to-teenagers-diverse-masses-throng-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-home</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/from-elders-to-teenagers-diverse-masses-throng-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-home</guid>
      <description>Published : Updated : Share this news Share this news</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/from-elders-to-teenagers-diverse-masses-throng-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-home">The Financial Express</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCP, Jamaat negotiate seat-sharing pact to contest in parliamentary polls</title>
      <link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-jamaat-negotiate-seat-sharing-pact-to-contest-in-parliamentary-polls</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-jamaat-negotiate-seat-sharing-pact-to-contest-in-parliamentary-polls</guid>
      <description>Published : Updated : Share this news The National Citizen Party (NCP) is holding talks with the Jamaat-e-Islami to form an alliance for the February elections, according to the parties’ leaders. A Facebook post by Abdul Kader, a former coordinator of the Students Against Discrimination and one of the leaders of the July Uprising, along with remarks from the parties’ top leaders, left clues to an election-time partnership between the two parties, based on seat sharing. “They have taken this suic...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-jamaat-negotiate-seat-sharing-pact-to-contest-in-parliamentary-polls">The Financial Express</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP to launch cleaning drive at July 36 Expressway (300-feet) on Friday morning</title>
      <link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-to-launch-cleaning-drive-at-july-36-expressway-300-feet-on-friday-morning</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-to-launch-cleaning-drive-at-july-36-expressway-300-feet-on-friday-morning</guid>
      <description>Published : Updated : Share this news Dhaka Metropolitan North unit of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) will conduct a voluntary clean-up drive tomorrow morning to remove waste generated following the massive public gathering held to mark the ‘historic homecoming’ of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman. BNP Media Cell Convener Professor Dr. Moudud Hossain Alamgir Pavel disclosed the information to the media on Friday. The cleaning operation will cover the July 36 Expressway (300-feet road), Air...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-to-launch-cleaning-drive-at-july-36-expressway-300-feet-on-friday-morning">The Financial Express</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman returns home amid rapturous reception</title>
      <link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-returns-home-amid-rapturous-reception</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-returns-home-amid-rapturous-reception</guid>
      <description>Published : Updated : Share this news Ending his 17 years in exile, BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman returned to Bangladesh on Thursday, greeted by a rapturous reception from hundreds of thousands of jubilant supporters, marking his homecoming as a historic and triumphant event. The BNP leader’s arrival marked a significant moment, as he set foot on Bangladeshi soil, felt the earth and dew-soaked grass beneath his feet, and pledged to work together with the people to build the country and impl...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-returns-home-amid-rapturous-reception">The Financial Express</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New books for primary students arrive in Rajshahi</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399559/new-books-for-primary-students-arrive-in-rajshahi</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399559/new-books-for-primary-students-arrive-in-rajshahi</guid>
      <description>New textbooks have started arriving at primary and secondary schools in Rajshahi. According to the education office, 100 percent of primary-level textbooks have already reached Rajshahi. However, all secondary-level books have not yet arrived here. In the first phase, all...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399559/new-books-for-primary-students-arrive-in-rajshahi">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:52:08 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP to clear all waste from 300 Feet Road Friday</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399554/bnp-to-clear-all-waste-from-300-feet-road-on</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399554/bnp-to-clear-all-waste-from-300-feet-road-on</guid>
      <description>Dhaka North BNP will remove all waste from the &amp;amp;lsquo;July 36 Expressway&amp;amp;rsquo; (300 Feet Road) following the &amp;amp;lsquo;historic return home&amp;amp;rsquo; of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman. The information was shared with the media on Thursday evening by Professor Dr Moudud Hossain...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399554/bnp-to-clear-all-waste-from-300-feet-road-on">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:32:56 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman to visit Ziaur Rahman’s grave Friday</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399558/tarique-rahman-to-visit-ziaur-rahman%E2%80%99s-grave-and</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399558/tarique-rahman-to-visit-ziaur-rahman%E2%80%99s-grave-and</guid>
      <description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will visit the grave of Ziaur Rahman in Sher-e-Bangla Nagar on Friday, on the second day after his return to the country, following the Juma prayers. He will later travel to the National Martyrs&amp;amp;rsquo; Memorial in Savar to pay tribute to the...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399558/tarique-rahman-to-visit-ziaur-rahman%E2%80%99s-grave-and">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:51:53 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fakhrul: We will win next election under Tarique Rahman’s leadership</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399552/mirza-fakhrul-we-will-win-the-next-election-under</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399552/mirza-fakhrul-we-will-win-the-next-election-under</guid>
      <description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said that under the leadership of Tarique Rahman, they ousted a fascist regime on August 5, 2024 and successfully navigated a difficult political journey. Expressing confidence, he said that, God willing, the party...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399552/mirza-fakhrul-we-will-win-the-next-election-under">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:25:33 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold wave continues in northern region disrupting normal</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399556/cold-wave-continues-in-northern-region-disrupting</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399556/cold-wave-continues-in-northern-region-disrupting</guid>
      <description>The mild cold wave sweeping across northern region of the country continued for the third consecutive day on Thursday, affecting normal life. While maximum temperatures rose slightly, minimum temperatures remained mostly unchanged, keeping the chill intact. The sky stayed...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399556/cold-wave-continues-in-northern-region-disrupting">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:28:44 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Political leaders react to Tarique Rahman’s homecoming</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/399567/political-leaders-react-to-tarique-rahman%E2%80%99s</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/399567/political-leaders-react-to-tarique-rahman%E2%80%99s</guid>
      <description>Leaders of major political parties and movements across Bangladesh on Thursday welcomed the return of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman after 17 years in exile, describing his homecoming as a significant moment in the country&amp;amp;rsquo;s democratic struggle rather than a personal...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/399567/political-leaders-react-to-tarique-rahman%E2%80%99s">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 01:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>302, including former home minister, sued over attempted murder case</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399577/302-including-former-home-minister-sued-over</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399577/302-including-former-home-minister-sued-over</guid>
      <description>A case of attempted murder dating back to July 2024 has been refiled in Bogra, naming 302 people as accused, including former Home Minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal. The case was lodged on Wednesday at Sadar Police Station by Md. Alif (25), son of Nur Hossain Mandal of West...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399577/302-including-former-home-minister-sued-over">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:19:13 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Dear Bangladesh’: Tarique Rahman returns home after 17 years</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399563/%E2%80%98dear-bangladesh%E2%80%99-tarique-rahman-returns-home</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399563/%E2%80%98dear-bangladesh%E2%80%99-tarique-rahman-returns-home</guid>
      <description>After 17 years and three months in exile, BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman returned to Bangladesh on Thursday, marking one of the most significant political homecomings in recent years. A Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight (BG-202) carrying Tarique Rahman landed at Hazrat...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/politics/399563/%E2%80%98dear-bangladesh%E2%80%99-tarique-rahman-returns-home">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:30:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five AL men held in Moulvibazar</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399574/five-al-men-held-in-moulvibazar</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399574/five-al-men-held-in-moulvibazar</guid>
      <description>Law enforcement agencies have arrested five leaders and activists of Awami League in Moulvibazar district on Thursday. The arrestees are: Russell Ahmed (33), Religious Affairs Secretary of Barlekha Upazila Swechchhasebak League; Tota Mia (65), Religious Affairs Secretary of...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399574/five-al-men-held-in-moulvibazar">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:09:57 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUBT honors female students at Aparajita Hall farewell ceremony</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399571/gubt-honors-female-students-at-aparajita-hall</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399571/gubt-honors-female-students-at-aparajita-hall</guid>
      <description>A farewell ceremony for the female students of Aparajita Hall at Gopalganj University of Science and Technology (GUBT) was held on Wednesday evening at a restaurant in Gopalganj town. The event was presided over by Aparajita Hall Provost Dr Rehena Parveen, while the...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399571/gubt-honors-female-students-at-aparajita-hall">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:02:49 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journalists form human chain in Khulna protesting attacks on Prothom Alo, Daily Star</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399573/journalists-form-human-chain-in-khulna-protesting</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399573/journalists-form-human-chain-in-khulna-protesting</guid>
      <description>Journalists in Khulna on Wednesday afternoon formed a human chain protesting the attacks, vandalism and arson at the offices of the country&amp;#x27;s two leading newspapers -- Prothom Alo and The Daily Star-- and demanding an end to harassment of media workers. The programme was held...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399573/journalists-form-human-chain-in-khulna-protesting">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:06:30 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3-day art camp launched in Naogaon</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399569/3-day-art-camp-launched-in-naogaon</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399569/3-day-art-camp-launched-in-naogaon</guid>
      <description>Naogaon hosted its first-ever three-day art camp on Thursday at Muktir Mor Zilla Parishad Park, organized by Visual Arts Naogaon. Veteran painter Rezaul Haque inaugurated the event. Among those present were KEDIAN President Anisur Rahman, Badruzzaman, former principal...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399569/3-day-art-camp-launched-in-naogaon">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:53:34 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Day celebrated in Rajshahi</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399570/christmas-day-celebrated-in-rajshahi</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399570/christmas-day-celebrated-in-rajshahi</guid>
      <description>Christmas Day, the largest religious festival of the Christian community, was celebrated here with much enthusiasm and festive mood on Thursday. Churches hold midnight mass and special morning prayers for Jesus Christ, seeking global peace and prosperity, with large...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399570/christmas-day-celebrated-in-rajshahi">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:15 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Ashrayan homes left abandoned in Shibganj</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399568/15-ashrayan-homes-left-abandoned-in-shibganj</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399568/15-ashrayan-homes-left-abandoned-in-shibganj</guid>
      <description>Fifteen homes built at Kanchithal village in Shibganj upazila of Bogra under the Ashrayan project have remained abandoned. The beneficiaries gradually left the houses over the past year, leaving them unused. As the families now live elsewhere, bushes and wild vegetation have...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399568/15-ashrayan-homes-left-abandoned-in-shibganj">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:48:11 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six more held over lynching of Hindu youth in Mymensingh</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399565/six-more-held-over-lynching-of-hindu-youth-in</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399565/six-more-held-over-lynching-of-hindu-youth-in</guid>
      <description>Police have arrested six more people during a raid at Bhaluka upazila in Mymensingh on Thursday in connection with the lynching of Dipu Chandra Das in Mymensingh district on 18 December. The arrestees are Takbir, 22, of Sunamganj; Ruhul Amin, 42, of Thakurgaon; Nur Alam, 33,...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399565/six-more-held-over-lynching-of-hindu-youth-in">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:32:53 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Youth found dead in Barguna</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399566/youth-found-dead-in-barguna</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399566/youth-found-dead-in-barguna</guid>
      <description>Police recovered the hanging body of a youth from Amtali upazila of Barguna district on Wednesday night. The deceased was identified as Md Limon, 21, a tenant at a house owned by Tahsin Molla in Khontakata area, adjacent to Baitul Aman Jame Mosque under Ward No. 3 of Amtali...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399566/youth-found-dead-in-barguna">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:37:28 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nation marks Christmas with devotion, festive cheer</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/399562/nation-marks-christmas-with-devotion-festive</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/399562/nation-marks-christmas-with-devotion-festive</guid>
      <description>Christmas Day, commemorating the birth of Jesus Christ, was celebrated across Bangladesh on Thursday with religious devotion, colourful festivities and renewed calls for peace, compassion and communal harmony. Churches across the country were illuminated with decorative...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/399562/nation-marks-christmas-with-devotion-festive">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 22:13:58 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 candidates collect nomination papers in Khulna</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399564/33-candidates-collect-nomination-papers-in-khulna</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399564/33-candidates-collect-nomination-papers-in-khulna</guid>
      <description>A total of 33 candidates from eight political parties have, so far, collected nomination papers in six parliamentary constituencies of Khulna ahead of the upcoming 13th national elections. Of them, 10 candidates are from the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), six from...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399564/33-candidates-collect-nomination-papers-in-khulna">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:27:43 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Month-long textile, cottage industries fair begins in Rajshahi</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399561/month-long-textile-cottage-industries-fair-begins</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399561/month-long-textile-cottage-industries-fair-begins</guid>
      <description>A month-long textile and cottage industries fair began in Rajshahi on Thursday with the call for bolstering the economic condition of the region through the revival of handloom and cottage goods productioin. Women Entrepreneurs Association of Bangladesh (WEAB) is...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/nation/399561/month-long-textile-cottage-industries-fair-begins">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 22:05:43 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka shivers at season’s lowest temperature</title>
      <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/399560/dhaka-shivers-as-season%E2%80%99s-lowest-temperature</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/399560/dhaka-shivers-as-season%E2%80%99s-lowest-temperature</guid>
      <description>Dhaka experienced the coldest day of the season on Thursday as fog and chilly winds swept across the capital, intensifying the wintery feel. The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) recorded the city&amp;amp;rsquo;s lowest temperature at 14.2&amp;amp;deg;C. Temperatures will...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/399560/dhaka-shivers-as-season%E2%80%99s-lowest-temperature">Dhaka Tribune</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:54:24 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In pictures: Tarique Rahman returns home</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/81wakzxv9b</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/81wakzxv9b</guid>
      <description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has arrived in the country. The Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight carrying Tarique Rahman landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka at 11:39 am on Thursday. He was accompanied by his wife Zubaida Rahman and daughter Zaima Rahman. BNP leaders and activists later welcomed Tarique Rahman and his family at the airport.At 12:35 pm, Tarique Rahman exited through the VIP gate. Standing at the front of the bus, he waved to the leaders and activists and o...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/81wakzxv9b">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:17:12 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now is the best time for a leader to become a statesman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/rhv5c3tdah</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/rhv5c3tdah</guid>
      <description>One of our distinguished poets, Helal Hafiz, wrote an outstanding poem titled “Forbidden Editorial.” Two widely quoted lines from the poem are:&amp;quot;Now is the prime of youth; Now is the time to go to war.&amp;quot;For our country, this is very much a “time of struggle”—a struggle to bring the nation back onto the right path. We are lost in thought, wondering who will lead us in this “struggle.” No one seems particularly promising. At this critical moment, we need a statesman. If poet Helal Hafiz were still a...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/rhv5c3tdah">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:52:31 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Tarique Rahman’s return is important</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/6mjkntth90</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/6mjkntth90</guid>
      <description>Ahead of Cambodia’s 2013 general election, two political parties—the Human Rights Party and the Sam Rainsy Party (later renamed the Candlelight Party)—merged in 2012 to form the Cambodian National Rescue Party (CNRP). In the 2013 election, the CNRP mounted an unexpectedly strong challenge to the ruling Cambodian People’s Party led by authoritarian Prime Minister Hun Sen. Of the 123 seats in parliament, the ruling party won 68, while the CNRP secured 55.Following this outcome, the CNRP came under...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/6mjkntth90">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:11:11 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National consensus: Tarique Rahman’s vision of new politics</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/n5tp6znobi</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/n5tp6znobi</guid>
      <description>Tarique Rahman has observed that hostile relations between the political parties are a major barrier to national progress. In an exchange of opinion meeting with grassroots leaders and workers of the BNP on 31 August 2024, he made it clear that they would not take revenge for the repression they had undergone in the past 17 years.“We’ll establish rule of justice,” he said. To him, political changeover does not mean mere transfer of power but qualitative change in the state. Thus, he promised tha...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/n5tp6znobi">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:41:29 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP allocates 4 seats to Jamiat Ulama-e-Islam</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/305vuq2c2h</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/305vuq2c2h</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has allocated four parliamentary constituencies to its partner in the joint political movement, Jamiat Ulama-e-Islam Bangladesh, for the forthcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election.This information was disclosed today, Tuesday, at a press conference held at the BNP chairperson’s political office in Gulshan by the party’s secretary general, Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir.It was stated at the press conference that the four seats allocated by BNP to Jamiat Ulama...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/305vuq2c2h">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:48:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economy under the dark cloud of violent politics</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/9ajfdkjyu7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/9ajfdkjyu7</guid>
      <description>The recent wave of violence has created deep anxiety in public life. The day after the Bangladesh Election Commission announced the schedule for the national election, on 12 December, young political leader Sharif Osman Hadi was shot by assailants in broad daylight. He later died while undergoing treatment in Singapore. Hadi’s killing sends a stark message, that expressing dissent has now become dangerous.This is not confined to politics alone. Attacks on two leading newspapers and two cultural ...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/9ajfdkjyu7">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:21:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editors’ Council, NOAB jointly hold protest meeting, human chain</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/u5vpnd37w1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/u5vpnd37w1</guid>
      <description>The Editors’ Council, the organisation of newspaper editors, and the Newspaper Owners’ Association of Bangladesh (NOAB) jointly organised a protest meeting and human chain titled ‘Bangladesh under Mob Violence’ in Dhaka on Monday. Leaders of various political parties, professional bodies, business organisations, journalists’ organisations, and representatives of civil society from different walks of life came to express solidarity. After the protest meeting, a human chain was held on the road be...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/u5vpnd37w1">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:49:30 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP leaves Brahmanbaria-2 to Jamiat; Rumeen, two other BNP leaders to contest as independents</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/7b38q2bbp0</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/7b38q2bbp0</guid>
      <description>Former reserved-seat lawmaker and BNP&amp;#x27;s international affairs assistant secretary Rumeen Farhana has not received the party nomination from the Brahmanbaria-2 constituency (Sarail–Ashuganj and parts of Bijoynagar). BNP has ceded the seat to Maulana Junayed Al Habib, vice president of the central committee of Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam Bangladesh.The information was disclosed on Tuesday at a press conference held at the BNP chairperson’s political office in Gulshan by the party’s Secretary General, Mir...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/7b38q2bbp0">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:19:08 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous conspiracy underway to obstruct transitional process: Mirza Fakhrul</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/pyqkxx8riy</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/pyqkxx8riy</guid>
      <description>Stating that Bangladesh is going through a “transitional process,” Mirza Fakhrul said, “Even now, it is apparent that certain individuals and quarters have undertaken a dangerous conspiracy to obstruct this transitional process.”Mirza Fakhrul made these remarks on Tuesday afternoon while addressing a press briefing at the BNP chairperson’s political office in Gulshan. Earlier, BNP held a meeting with leaders of Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam Bangladesh. He also announced that four seats would be allotted ...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/pyqkxx8riy">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:10:40 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite ‘risks’, Asif Mahmud collects nomination form to contest election</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/qc5v42bap2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/qc5v42bap2</guid>
      <description>Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuiyan, who resigned from his position as an adviser, personally went to the local election office to collect a nomination form to contest the 13th parliamentary election from the Dhaka–10 constituency. The July uprising leader also stated that he is aware his personal safety is currently at risk.A former student of the University of Dhaka and a frontline leader of the July uprising as a coordinator of the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement, Asif Mahmud took the oath as an ...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/qc5v42bap2">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:53:51 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Had I resigned I wouldn’t be sitting here: Home Affairs Adviser</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/government/7ye3pj7vkl</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/government/7ye3pj7vkl</guid>
      <description>Responding to rumours about his resignation, Home Affairs Adviser Lieutenant General (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said, “If I had resigned, I would not be sitting here.”He made the comment at a press conference at the conference room of the Ministry of Home Affairs at the Secretariat on Monday, in response to a question from a journalist after the 18th meeting of the Advisory Council Committee on Law and Order.Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said that today’s meeting discussed overall security prep...</description>
      <category>government</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/government/7ye3pj7vkl">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:11:04 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 special trains allocated for leaders, activists attending Tarique Rahman’s reception</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/gh59tc0mwk</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/gh59tc0mwk</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Railway is set to operate 10 special trains to bring people to the programme organised to mark the return of BNP’s acting chairman Tarique Rahman to the country. Following BNP’s request, the railway will provide these special trains next Thursday in exchange for the fare. In addition, extra coaches will be added to regular trains for the convenience of those attending the rally.A press release from the Ministry of Railways announced the operation of these special trains. The railway w...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/gh59tc0mwk">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 22:00:50 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attacks on Prothom Alo, Daily Star, 2 cultural organisations: 31 suspects identified, 9 arrested</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/27gbd5rft9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/27gbd5rft9</guid>
      <description>Law enforcement agencies have arrested at least nine people in raids carried out across Dhaka and other parts of the country up to Monday morning in connection with attacks on the offices of the national dailies Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, as well as two cultural organisations, Chhayanaut and Udichi.The information was disclosed in a press release posted on the chief adviser’s verified Facebook page at 10:31 am today, Monday.Late on Thursday (18 December) night, assailants vandalised and loo...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/27gbd5rft9">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:01:45 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politicians seek security, gunmen to government</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/yhxd06zsdo</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/yhxd06zsdo</guid>
      <description>Several politicians have applied to the government seeking security. Some have requested a police team to provide protection. Others have asked for armed guards or gunmen. Some have applied for firearms licenses.Amid growing concern over the country’s law and order situation, such applications are being submitted to the Ministry of Home Affairs on behalf of politicians. Some have sought both security and firearms licenses at the same time.Sources at the Ministry of Home Affairs said that applica...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/yhxd06zsdo">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:28:56 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It was not just an attack on Prothom Alo-Daily Star, it is an attack on democracy: Mirza Fakhrul</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/9icpwtrdiz</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/9icpwtrdiz</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said that this is not only an attack on Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, it is an attack on democracy itself. So, he said all pro-democracy forces must unite to resist this evil force.Mirza Fakhrul made the remarks while expressing solidarity at a protest rally organised in response to the attacks and arson at the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, as well as the harassment of Nurul Kabir, editor of New A...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/9icpwtrdiz">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:20:30 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How BNP wants to build the country</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/0vfp9007kh</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/0vfp9007kh</guid>
      <description>Perhaps for the first time in Bangladesh’s history, a political party has arranged training for its own leaders and activists to ensure that its specific programmes reach everyone, from urban citizens to marginalised communities. From 7 to 13 December, BNP provided training on eight topics to leaders and activists from its affiliated organisations as well as the main party.The “Nation-Building Programme” functioned not only as a set of training workshops, but also, through these workshops, outli...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/0vfp9007kh">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:41:16 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP gets permission to hold reception for Tarique Rahman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/y7j6o96mm9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/y7j6o96mm9</guid>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has received permission from the Dhaka divisional commissioner to organise a reception marking the return home of its acting chairman, Tarique Rahman, reports BSS.The matter was confirmed Sunday night by BNP Media Cell member Shairul Kabir Khan. After spending 17 years in exile in London, UK, Tarique Rahman is set to return to Bangladesh on 25 December. Shairul Kabir Khan said the party has received written approval to organise the reception to mark the act...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/y7j6o96mm9">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:48:18 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nomination papers collected on behalf of Khaleda Zia and Tarique Rahman in Bogura</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/ldz0wa7lpx</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/ldz0wa7lpx</guid>
      <description>Ahead of the 13th national parliamentary election, nomination papers have been collected on behalf of BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia for the Bogura-7 (Gabtali–Shajahanpur) constituency, and on behalf of the party’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman for the Bogura-6 (Sadar) constituency.Around 1:30 pm today, Sunday, Khaleda Zia’s adviser and former MP Helaluzzaman Talukder collected the nomination papers on her behalf from the office of the district election officer in the Khandar area of the cit...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/ldz0wa7lpx">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:31:21 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some are trying to create anarchy in the country: Tarique Rahman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/local-news/spevbkbe5a</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/local-news/spevbkbe5a</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) acting chairman Tarique Rahman has warned party leaders and activists to remain vigilant, saying the days ahead will not be easy. Anarchy has begun in different parts of the country, and some are trying to create disorder. Everyone must stay alert, he said.Tarique Rahman made these remarks today, Sunday afternoon while speaking online as the chief guest at the inauguration of a digital memorial for the July martyrs at the Shaheed Titu Auditorium in Edward Park,...</description>
      <category>local news</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/local-news/spevbkbe5a">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:53:51 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overall law and order situation under control: EC</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/q6tql3lkg0</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/q6tql3lkg0</guid>
      <description>Despite concerns among political parties following the murder of potential candidate Sharif Osman Hadi, the Election Commission (EC) believes that the overall law and order situation in the country remains under control.Speaking to newspersons today, Sunday, after a meeting of the EC with the three service chiefs, Election Commissioner Brigadier General Abul Fazal Md Sanaullah (Retd.) said, “There are internal disputes within parties and conflicts among multiple parties. But overall, if we asses...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/q6tql3lkg0">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 21:38:54 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Country can&amp;#x27;t move forward amid so much division and crisis: Matiur Rahman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/uy3h9c31il</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/uy3h9c31il</guid>
      <description>Prothom Alo Editor Matiur Rahman has said that creating an environment of national unity and reconciliation is now the most important task for Bangladesh.“No country can survive with so much conflict, so much division, and so many crises. Nor can any government effectively run a country under such conditions,” he said.Matiur Rahman made the remarks at a view exchange meeting organised on the occasion of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s “historic return to the homeland.”The meeting was held o...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/uy3h9c31il">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:18:22 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Mobocracy’ became rampant due to government weakness: Salahuddin Ahmed</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/6opa87arm4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/6opa87arm4</guid>
      <description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed has said that the attacks and arson on the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star have damaged Bangladesh’s image worldwide, blaming government weakness for allowing what he termed “mobocracy” to become rampant. He said such tendencies must be suppressed firmly.He made the remarks on Sunday afternoon at a discussion meeting with senior media figures, organised to mark BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s “historic homecoming day,” at the Radisson...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/6opa87arm4">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:13:39 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police find no ‘credible’ evidence of sabotage</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/receev0w5v</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/receev0w5v</guid>
      <description>As of Sunday noon, no case has been filed at Lakshmipur Sadar police station in connection with a fire at the home of a BNP leader. Police say they have not found credible evidence that the incident resulted from sabotage. The fire service has expressed a similar view. However, the BNP leader claims that the door was locked from the outside, preventing him from escaping.The matter was disclosed in a press release signed on Saturday night by Hossain Mohammad Raihan Kazemi, additional superintende...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/receev0w5v">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:56:16 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New kind of ‘media environment’ is essential to build a new Bangladesh: Mahfuz Anam</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/2w4fagwg0o</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/2w4fagwg0o</guid>
      <description>Recalling the experience that no government in Bangladesh’s 53-year political history has truly accepted critical journalism, The Daily Star editor Mahfuz Anam has called for the acceptance of an independent and critical media in the new Bangladesh.He made the remarks at a discussion meeting organised on the occasion of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s “historic return home.” The meeting was held this afternoon (Sunday) at the Radisson Blu, with editors of daily newspapers and online news po...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/2w4fagwg0o">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:56:32 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US univs seed start-ups</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/US-univs-seed-start-ups</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/US-univs-seed-start-ups</guid>
      <description>A decade ago, Devin Jameson might have chosen to drop out of college and work on Eversound, a wireless headset start-up for senior communities. Instead, Jameson was able to combine his co-founded company with his academic coursework through Cornell University’s eLab program, an accelerator curriculum he completed in 2015. The eLab program runs for a full academic year. Students build out their businesses while participating in lectures, class work, mentorship and receiving a $5,000 investment. A...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/US-univs-seed-start-ups">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 09:49:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>313,848 posts remain vacant under different ministries</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/313-848-posts-remain-vacant-at-different</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/313-848-posts-remain-vacant-at-different</guid>
      <description>State minister for public administration on Sunday told parliament that a total of 313,848 posts remain vacant under different ministries, reports UNB.In reply to a query from Jatiya Party MP Mujibul Haque Chunnu, the state minister said as many as 313,848 posts fell vacant at different ministries.The state minister also said some 290 government officials are currently serving as officers on special duty (OSD) while 177 officials and employees are working at different ministries and departments ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/313-848-posts-remain-vacant-at-different">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 20:55:56 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JU to host job fair Sunday</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/JU-to-organise-job-fair-Sunday</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/JU-to-organise-job-fair-Sunday</guid>
      <description>A job fair titled &amp;#x27;Career Boot Camp Campus Recruitment-2019&amp;#x27; will be held at Jahangirnagar University on Sunday.Jahangirnagar University Career Club (JUCC) is organising the fair at the seminar room of Zahir Raihan auditorium where Kazi IT Center will recruit fresh graduates from the university. JUCC president Hadi Siam made the disclosure at a press meet at Jahangirnagar University Journalists&amp;#x27; Association (JUJA) office on Saturday afternoon. &amp;quot;For the first time, we&amp;#x27;re going to introduce a mult...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/JU-to-organise-job-fair-Sunday">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 21:40:04 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BYLC awards winners of Youth Entrepreneurship Challenge</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BYLC-awards-winners-of-Youth-Entrepreneurship</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BYLC-awards-winners-of-Youth-Entrepreneurship</guid>
      <description>The winners of the Youth Entrepreneurship Challenge (YEC), a social initiative by Bangladesh Youth Leadership Center (BYLC) to encourage and promote the promising entrepreneurs, have been announced at a ceremony in the city, reports UNB. The YEC, an initiative under BYLC’s entrepreneurship development wing in association with DFID and Manusher Jonno Foundation, is part of the organisation’s efforts to nurture the passion of aspiring entrepreneurs with unique revenue-generating business ideas by ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BYLC-awards-winners-of-Youth-Entrepreneurship">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 17:58:45 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deepa Mehta finds reality cautionary, not scary</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Deepa-Mehta-finds-reality-cautionary-not-scary</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Deepa-Mehta-finds-reality-cautionary-not-scary</guid>
      <description>The dystopian world of Deepa Mehta&amp;#x27;s “Leila” is not a subliminal, but a blunt reminder of the world that could be in reality. An acclaimed filmmaker, whose brand of cinema has been fearless in confronting the harsh truths of the society, says showcasing reality is merely cautionary and not meant to be scary. &amp;quot;Leila&amp;quot;, adapted from Prayaag Akbar&amp;#x27;s eponymous novel, is a dark and ominous tale set in the fictional world of Aryavarta, where a leader&amp;#x27;s motto delves on &amp;#x27;peace by segregation&amp;#x27; and where c...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Deepa-Mehta-finds-reality-cautionary-not-scary">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 11:44:32 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Govt working to create 15m jobs in 5 years’</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/‘Govt-working-to-create-15m-jobs-in-5-years’</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/‘Govt-working-to-create-15m-jobs-in-5-years’</guid>
      <description>Prime minister and leader of the house Sheikh Hasina on Wednesday told the Jatiya Sangsad that her government has set a target of creating 15 million employments in the next five years. “Yes, it’s true that our government has set a goal of creating 15 million employments in the next five years,” she said in reply to a starred question from treasury bench member M Abdul Latif (Chattogram) during her question hour in the house. The prime minister said on the basis of the strategies and targets of ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/‘Govt-working-to-create-15m-jobs-in-5-years’">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 11:52:39 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singer Shahnaz Rahmatuallah dies</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Singer-Shahnaz-Rahmatuallah-dies</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Singer-Shahnaz-Rahmatuallah-dies</guid>
      <description>Celebrated singer Shahnaz Rahmatuallah died of heart attack on Saturday night. She was 65. Shahnaz breathed her last at her Baridhaara residence around 11:30pm after suffering a heart attack, dancer Doly Iqbal confirmed Prothom Alo. The singer left behind her husband, a son and a daughter and well-wishers to mourn. Shahnaz’s husband retired major Abul Bashar Rahmatullah said the namaaz-e-janaza of the singer will be held at Park Mosque near the road no. 9 of Baridhara residential area after the ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Singer-Shahnaz-Rahmatuallah-dies">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 08:56:20 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube, farming, cleaning jobs abroad rise as alternatives</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/YouTube-farming-cleaning-jobs-abroad-rise-as</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/YouTube-farming-cleaning-jobs-abroad-rise-as</guid>
      <description>Yoon Chang-hyun&amp;#x27;s parents told him to get his sanity checked when he quit his secure job as a researcher at Samsung Electronics Co in 2015 to start his own YouTube channel.The 65 million won ($57,619) a year salary - triple South Korea&amp;#x27;s average entry level wage - plus top-notch healthcare and other benefits offered by the world&amp;#x27;s biggest smartphone and memory chip maker was the envy of many college graduates.But burned out and disillusioned by repeated night shifts, narrowing opportunities for ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/YouTube-farming-cleaning-jobs-abroad-rise-as">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:35:18 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BREB to recruit 2000 line crews</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BREB-to-recruit-2000-line-crews</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BREB-to-recruit-2000-line-crews</guid>
      <description>BREB’s Palli Bidyut Samity will recruit some 2,000 line ‘crew level-1’.Bangladesh Rural Electrification Board (BREB) has published a circular in this regard, inviting the eligible candidates to apply for the posts.Eligibility: the applicants must have Secondary School Certificate (SSC) or equivalent exams degree with minimum CGPA of 2.5 (out of 5). Science background students will get priority. Applicants must be 18-22 years old on 1 April 2019. The age limit, however, is flexible up to 25 years...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BREB-to-recruit-2000-line-crews">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 17:57:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&amp;#x27;Good men do bad things&amp;#x27;: Cheryl on #MeToo</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Good-men-do-bad-things-Cheryl-on-MeToo</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Good-men-do-bad-things-Cheryl-on-MeToo</guid>
      <description>Bestselling author Cheryl Strayed, whose memoir &amp;quot;Wild&amp;quot; was turned into an Oscar-nominated film about her recovery from trauma, says listening more is key to healing wounds between men and women in the age of #MeToo. Published in 2012, &amp;quot;Wild&amp;quot; -- which recounted Strayed&amp;#x27;s gruelling 1,100-mile solo hike along the Pacific Crest Trail in America at the age of 26 -- was a smash hit that prompted Oprah Winfrey to resurrect her book club. Two years later, the film starring Reese Witherspoon catapulted U...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Good-men-do-bad-things-Cheryl-on-MeToo">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 15:28:42 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curtain falls on Dhaka International Folk Fest Saturday</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Curtain-falls-on-Dhaka-International-Folk-Fest</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Curtain-falls-on-Dhaka-International-Folk-Fest</guid>
      <description>Las Migas from Spain and Shafqat Amanat Ali from Pakistan are scheduled to come to this bustling city to celebrate the spirit of folk music on the final day of the Dhaka International Folk Fest on Saturday. Baul Kabir Shah, Arnob, Nakshikatha, Swarobanjo and Bhabna Nritya Dol of the host country will also be performing on the third day, reports UNB. DIKANDA from Poland, Wadali Brothers and Satyaki Banerjee from India and Abdul Hai Dewan from Bangladesh performed on the first day of the three-day...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Curtain-falls-on-Dhaka-International-Folk-Fest">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 11:12:48 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mrinal Sen no more</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Filmmaker-Mrinal-Sen-passes-away</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Filmmaker-Mrinal-Sen-passes-away</guid>
      <description>Mrinal Sen, legendary filmmaker of Indian cinema based in West Bengal, is no more. Sen died of a cardiac arrest at his residence in Kolkata&amp;#x27;s Bhabanipur on Sunday, according to UNB. He was 95. Tracing his roots to Faridpur in Bangladesh, Sen was born on 14 May, 1923. He has directed a handful of critically acclaimed films that put Bangla cinema on the map including &amp;quot;Baishe Srabon&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Chorus&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Akaler Sandhaney&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Bhuvan Shome&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Parasuram&amp;quot; and more. His fanbase, not surprisingly, spanned both in ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Filmmaker-Mrinal-Sen-passes-away">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 19:34:42 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portal to provide job services to unemployed youths</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Portal-to-provide-job-services-to-unemployed</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Portal-to-provide-job-services-to-unemployed</guid>
      <description>Kolorob Jobs, a digital job portal to create job opportunities for unemployed and vulnerable youths, was launched in the city on Sunday, reports UNB. The website is a project of Save the Children in Bangladesh. The aim of the platform is to make job placement easier for unemployed and vulnerable youth jobseekers in Bangladesh, said Mark Taylor Pierce, country director of Save the Children. He added that employers can recruit qualified semi-skilled and skilled workers for blue collar jobs using t...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Portal-to-provide-job-services-to-unemployed">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 12:20:34 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rock inspiration for the young</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Rock-inspiration-for-the-young</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Rock-inspiration-for-the-young</guid>
      <description>“We need to take care of young talent. Please take care of young talents - guitarists, drummers or keyboardists, whoever he or she is,” said Bangladesh&amp;#x27;s rock legend Ayub Bachchu, appealing to the people on behalf of up-and-coming musicians in a TV interview. Bachchu unexpectedly passed away on Thursday. Having gone through hardships at the beginning of his career, the multi-talented singer and songwriter wanted to ensure young talent across the country got the support they need. “This world is ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Rock-inspiration-for-the-young">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 15:21:15 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selim Al Deen festivals begin at Shilpakala Academy</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Selim-Al-Deen-festivals-begin-at-Shilpakala</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Selim-Al-Deen-festivals-begin-at-Shilpakala</guid>
      <description>Marking the 69th birth anniversary of Natyacharya Selim Al Deen, two separate festivals began on the premises of Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy (BSA) in the capital on Friday, says UNB.Two theatre troops--Dhaka Theater and Swapnadal--separately organised the events marking the birth anniversary of the veteran artisan.As a part of the celebration, Swapnadal organised a discussion event on Friday at the Studio Theatre Hall of BSA while theatre personality Ataur Rahman was present as chief guest.Dir...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Selim-Al-Deen-festivals-begin-at-Shilpakala">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 10:18:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of any artwork is subjective: Sujoy Ghosh</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Evaluation-of-any-artwork-is-subjective-Sujoy</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Evaluation-of-any-artwork-is-subjective-Sujoy</guid>
      <description>India’s national award-winning filmmaker Sujoy Ghosh says engaging an audience must be the priority for any artwork, and the technicalities come later.The &amp;quot;Kahaani&amp;quot; director is in support of a short films award -- Critics Choice Short Film Awards (CCSFA) -- constituted by the Film Critics Guild&amp;#x27;s. Ghosh believes critics&amp;#x27; opinion on films are personal and subjective, whereas for the viewer, engagement is paramount.Asked about how he sets the parameters for critical analysis of a movie, Ghosh told...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Evaluation-of-any-artwork-is-subjective-Sujoy">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 17:52:18 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Library goers increase but not book lovers</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Library-goers-increase-but-not-book-lovers</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Library-goers-increase-but-not-book-lovers</guid>
      <description>Increasing number of young people visit these days libraries run by the government, despite apparent decline in the habit of reading books, according to users and authorities. Most of those seen in the libraries in recent times are actually candidates of Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) examinations, who use quiet atmosphere of the libraries for taking preparations. The increased presence of readers at libraries is understood by the rise in membership application in recent years, library authoriti...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Library-goers-increase-but-not-book-lovers">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 12:27:23 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dance star Akram Khan returns with last solo show</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Dance-star-Akram-Khan-returns-with-last-solo-show</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Dance-star-Akram-Khan-returns-with-last-solo-show</guid>
      <description>Britain&amp;#x27;s best-known choreographer Akram Khan has drawn on his roots for the final solo dance performance of his career, with a show that pays tribute to Indian soldiers who fought in World War I. &amp;quot;Xenos&amp;quot; -- which means stranger in Greek -- opens with two musicians on stage, playing an interpretation of Indian music in a festive atmosphere. Dressed for a performance, a dancer arrives, stumbling. The lights flicker, the music stalls and the dancer, a former soldier, is overcome by memories of war...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Dance-star-Akram-Khan-returns-with-last-solo-show">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 11:39:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overseas jobs panacea for youth unemployment?</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Overseas-jobs-panacea-for-youth-unemployment</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Overseas-jobs-panacea-for-youth-unemployment</guid>
      <description>Absorbing all unemployed youth into the job market is a daunting task that is not unique for Bangladesh. As nations observe the World Youth Skills Day Monday (July 15), what Bangladesh needs to do is instil skills into young, working-age people, making them market-ready for overseas jobs. The United Nations recognises rising youth unemployment as one of the most significant problems of developed and developing countries. Some 475 million new jobs need to be created over the next decade to absorb...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Overseas-jobs-panacea-for-youth-unemployment">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 12:14:08 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustafizur elated to be part of KKR in IPL</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/k4wo6ft78m</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/k4wo6ft78m</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh pacer Mustafizur Rahman was ecstatic to be part of Kolkata Knight Riders (KKR) for the first time in his Indian Premier League (IPL) career.&amp;quot;Hello KKR fans. I am Mustafizur Rahman. I am very happy and excited to be a part of the KKR team. See you soon,&amp;quot; Mustafizur said through a video message posted in KKR&amp;#x27;s social media handle.KKR secured Mustafizur&amp;#x27;s services for a whopping INR 92 million, making him the highest-paid Bangladeshi player in IPL history at the mini auction, held in Abu...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/k4wo6ft78m">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:37:12 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia all out for 371 in 3rd Ashes Test</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/kogzmbczny</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/kogzmbczny</guid>
      <description>Australia added a valuable 45 runs for their remaining two first innings wickets on day two of the third Ashes Test Thursday before being dismissed by England for 371.The hosts resumed on 326-8 with Mitchell Starc not out 33 and Nathan Lyon yet to score with temperatures soaring towards a forecast 39 Celsius at Adelaide Oval.Starc plundered five quick boundaries before being bowled by Jofra Archer for 54. Lyon and Scott Boland then piled on more misery for the tourists in a 23-run last-wicket st...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/kogzmbczny">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:05:48 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quota protesters stage demo demanding gazette</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Quota-protesters-stage-demo-demanding-gazette</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Quota-protesters-stage-demo-demanding-gazette</guid>
      <description>Quota protesters on Sunday staged a two-hour demonstration in colleges and universities across the country demanding immediate issuance of gazette notification abolishing quota system in public services. Agitated students began observing their strike around 11:00am by suspending classes and examinations, reports UNB. The demonstrators hold a human chain on Dhaka University campus demanding the issuance of gazette notification as per the announcement made by prime minister Sheikh Hasina in parlia...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Quota-protesters-stage-demo-demanding-gazette">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 13:43:40 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&amp;#x27;Golden moment&amp;#x27; as Messi meets Tendulkar on India tour</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/yg0chtianf</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/yg0chtianf</guid>
      <description>Football icon Lionel Messi&amp;#x27;s second day in India passed smoothly Sunday, after a chaotic opening to his three-day tour, as the World Cup winner kicked balls into the crowd and met cricket legend Sachin Tendulkar.Messi greeted excited fans decked out in Argentina football jerseys at a packed Wankhede stadium in India&amp;#x27;s financial hub Mumbai, as supporters chanted his name.The 38-year-old Argentina and Inter Miami superstar took centre stage in the presence of India&amp;#x27;s sporting royalty including Ten...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/yg0chtianf">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:51:05 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khawaja makes the most of late lifeline as Australia reach 194 for 5</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/5mo1p106dr</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/5mo1p106dr</guid>
      <description>Usman Khawaja hit a defiant 82 Wednesday after being thrown a lifeline at the third Ashes Test in Adelaide as England fought hard in searing heat to stay in the contest at tea on day one.Batting after captain Pat Cummins won the toss as temperatures topped 36 Celsius, the hosts were 194-5 after the shock news of Steve Smith being ruled out with illness.At the break, Alex Carey was not out 48 and Josh Inglis on five.Smith, who has more than 10,000 runs, had been feeling unwell in the lead-up but ...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/5mo1p106dr">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:36:08 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSG ordered to pay around 60m euros to Mbappe in wage dispute</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/abdzdly81d</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/abdzdly81d</guid>
      <description>Paris Saint-Germain were ordered by a French labour court to pay their former forward Kylian Mbappe up to 61 million euros ($71.8 million) in unpaid wages and bonuses on Tuesday.France captain Mbappe, who left PSG in June 2024 to join Real Madrid, had been claiming over 260 million euros in total from his former club.PSG in turn had demanded Mbappe pay them 440 million euros.Mbappe, 26, also claimed the Qatari-owned reigning European champions had applied the wrong French legal classification to...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/abdzdly81d">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:46:50 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abrar powers Bangladesh to victory in U19 Asia Cup opener</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gvv1zkkaia</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gvv1zkkaia</guid>
      <description>Opener Jawad Abarar hit a brilliant 96-run knock as Bangladesh Under-19 team made a winning start to the Under-19 Asia Cup with a three-wicket victory over Afghanistan at ICC Cricket Stadium in Dubai today.Electing to bat first, Afghanistan youngsters posted a respectable 283-7, riding on a fluent century of Faisal Shinozada, who hammered a 94 ball-103, featuring eight fours and four sixes.Abarar whose innings included nine fours and six sixes was instrumental in chasing the challenging total as...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gvv1zkkaia">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 21:46:04 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Zealand thrash West Indies for 1-0 Test series lead as Duffy takes 5</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/xj7h4728rs</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/xj7h4728rs</guid>
      <description>Jacob Duffy took five wickets as New Zealand cruised to a nine-wicket victory over the West Indies in the second Test in Wellington on Friday for a 1-0 series lead.Seamer Duffy took 5-38 from 17.2 overs, his second five-wicket haul in Tests, as the West Indies were rolled for 128 after lunch on day three, the hosts needing just 56 for victory.Devon Conway (28) and Kane Williamson (16) guided New Zealand to the emphatic win just before tea at the Basin Reserve. Debutant Michael Rae took 3-45 whil...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/xj7h4728rs">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:41:29 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh U19 confirms Asia Cup semifinal</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/oishjluje3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/oishjluje3</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Under-19 team confirmed the semifinal of Asia Cup after Sri Lanka edged past Afghanistan by two wickets in a tight contest at ICC Academy in Dubai, UAE Monday.The outcome of the match saw Sri Lanka youngsters also moved to the last four stage in the regional tournament. The last match between the Bangladesh and Sri Lanka on Wednesday will decide the group champions.Bangladesh earlier beat Afghanistan by three wickets and Nepal by seven wickets. Apart from beating Afghanistan by two wi...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/oishjluje3">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:59:36 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man City edge Real Madrid to leave Alonso on brink</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/qqe0affvnu</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/qqe0affvnu</guid>
      <description>Manchester City came from behind to beat Real Madrid 2-1 on Wednesday in the Champions League and leave Xabi Alonso&amp;#x27;s position as coach of the Spanish giants in grave danger.Without injured superstar Kylian Mbappe, Madrid took the lead through Rodrygo Goes but Nico O&amp;#x27;Reilly and an Erling Haaland penalty sent City in ahead at the break and ultimately secured Pep Guardiola&amp;#x27;s City the three points.Spanish media reported in the lead-up to the game that a defeat would seal Alonso&amp;#x27;s fate as Madrid coa...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/qqe0affvnu">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:46:55 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fans vandalise India stadium after Messi&amp;#x27;s abrupt exit</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/osgh4lctdk</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/osgh4lctdk</guid>
      <description>Angry spectators broke down barricades and stormed the pitch at a stadium in India after football star Lionel Messi, who is on a three-day tour of the country, abruptly left the arena.As a part of a so-called GOAT Tour, the 38-year-old Argentina and Inter Miami superstar touched down in the eastern state of West Bengal early Saturday, greeted by a chorus of exuberant fans chanting his name.Hours later, thousands of fans wearing Messi jerseys and waving the Argentine flag packed into Salt Lake st...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/osgh4lctdk">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:32:28 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kounde double helps Barcelona claim Frankfurt comeback win</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/4uidp3kbbw</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/4uidp3kbbw</guid>
      <description>Unlikely goalscoring hero Jules Kounde bagged two headers to help Barcelona beat Eintracht Frankfurt 2-1 on Tuesday in the Champions League and bolster the club&amp;#x27;s chances of a top-eight league phase finish.Ansgar Knauff sent the visitors into a surprise lead but French defender Kounde&amp;#x27;s brace early in the second half put last season&amp;#x27;s semi-finalists in control.In the club&amp;#x27;s first Champions League match back at Camp Nou since 2022, they gained revenge against a Frankfurt side who humiliated them ...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/4uidp3kbbw">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:15:23 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Captain Cummins back in Australia squad for 3rd Test</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/evskqr71y2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/evskqr71y2</guid>
      <description>Australia captain Pat Cummins is in line to return for the third Ashes Test against England in Adelaide after being named in a 15-man squad on Wednesday.Cummins is the only addition to an otherwise unchanged squad from Brisbane, where Australia won by eight wickets to take a 2-0 lead in the five-match series.The 32-year-old Cummins has been sidelined since the tour to the West Indies in July with a lower back injury. &amp;quot;We feel as though he&amp;#x27;ll be as best prepared as can be,&amp;quot; Australia coach Andrew...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/evskqr71y2">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:33:36 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Messi dazzles as Miami beat Vancouver to win MLS title</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/eec7k55slb</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/eec7k55slb</guid>
      <description>Lionel Messi inspired Inter Miami to their first ever MLS Cup title on Saturday, playing a starring role in a 3-1 victory over the Vancouver Whitecaps in Florida.Argentina superstar Messi provided assists for two goals and helped create another to spark wild celebrations before a rapturous home crowd at the Chase Stadium in Fort Lauderdale.&amp;quot;This is the the moment that I&amp;#x27;ve been waiting for, and that we as a team have been waiting for,&amp;quot; Messi, named MLS Cup Most Valuable Player, said afterwards.M...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/eec7k55slb">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 18:21:59 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026 World Cup: FIFA reveals tournament schedule</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/w6dfwek1li</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/w6dfwek1li</guid>
      <description>The path to glory at the 2026 World Cup has now been laid out with FIFA on Saturday confirming the full match schedule for the first 48-team tournament, a day after the star-studded draw ceremony in Washington dominated by Donald Trump.Saturday’s event hosted by FIFA president Gianni Infantino revealed that Lionel Messi’s Argentina, the reigning champions, will begin their defense of the trophy against Algeria in Group J in Kansas City on June 16. They will then face Austria and Jordan in Dallas...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/w6dfwek1li">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:29:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia crush England by eight wickets for 2-0 lead</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/pa75n0nzp4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/pa75n0nzp4</guid>
      <description>Australia cruised to an emphatic eight-wicket win over England in the day-night second Ashes Test in Brisbane on Sunday for an ominous 2-0 lead in the series.Set a paltry target of 65 for victory, Australia captain Steve Smith pulled Gus Atkinson for a huge six over square leg to get the job done in style.Although not as humiliating as the two-day loss in the first Test at Perth, England were comprehensively outplayed in every department.Australia are now overwhelming favourites to retain the As...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/pa75n0nzp4">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 17:44:26 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump takes centre stage as 2026 FIFA World Cup draw takes place</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/u2qa87y5o5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/u2qa87y5o5</guid>
      <description>The draw for the 2026 World Cup took place in Washington on Friday, with US President Donald Trump playing a prominent part in a star-studded ceremony that will map the path to glory for contenders at the first ever 48-team finals.Before the draw began at the Kennedy Center, FIFA chief Gianni Infantino, who has built a close relationship with Trump, awarded the US president FIFA&amp;#x27;s inaugural peace prize.FIFA says the honor &amp;quot;recognizes the enormous efforts of those individuals who unite people, br...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/u2qa87y5o5">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 08:42:28 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIFA World Cup draw: Who’s in which group? Argentina with Algeria, Austria, Jordan; Brazil set for key tests</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/l7z3ke1kqb</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/l7z3ke1kqb</guid>
      <description>Following is the draw for next year&amp;#x27;s 48-team World Cup, which will be held in the United States, Canada and Mexico from 11 July to 19 June 2026. Group A MexicoSouth AfricaSouth KoreaEuropean Playoff D Group B CanadaEuropean Playoff AQatarSwitzerland Group C BrazilMoroccoHaitiScotland Group D United StatesParaguayAustraliaEuropean Playoff C Group E GermanyCuracaoIvory CoastEcuador Group F NetherlandsJapanEuropean Playoff BTunisia Group G BelgiumEgyptIranNew Zealand Group H SpainCape VerdeSaudi A...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/l7z3ke1kqb">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:37:47 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epic Greaves double ton earns Windies draw in first NZ Test</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/ynrc44qp2p</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/ynrc44qp2p</guid>
      <description>An epic 202 not out by Justin Greaves and a stubborn support role by Kemar Roach saw the West Indies salvage a valiant draw in the first Test against New Zealand in Christchurch on Saturday.Set a colossal target of 531, 113 more than the current record for a successful fourth-innings chase, the West Indies were 457-6 at the end, the second-highest Test fourth innings.Greaves battled for almost 10 hours and faced 388 deliveries, bringing up his maiden double century in the penultimate over.Roach ...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/ynrc44qp2p">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 12:33:26 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ravindra, Latham tons put New Zealand in command against West Indies</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/c6ut7qy4ml</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/c6ut7qy4ml</guid>
      <description>Big centuries by Tom Latham and Rachin Ravindra put New Zealand firmly in control of the first Test against the West Indies with a lead of 481 at stumps on day three in Christchurch on Thursday.The pair put on 279 for the third wicket before Latham was out for 145. Ravindra followed soon after for 176.At stumps, Will Young was 21, Michael Bracewell was on six and New Zealand were 417-4 to go with their 64-run first innings lead.&amp;quot;If you asked what a perfect day looked like it would probably look ...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/c6ut7qy4ml">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:09:34 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hope&amp;#x27;s resistance keeps West Indies alive against New Zealand</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/i31g8ux7wn</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/i31g8ux7wn</guid>
      <description>A sparkling century by Shai Hope ably supported by Justin Greaves had the West Indies 212-4 at stumps on Friday and clinging to the remote chance they can save the first Test against New Zealand in Christchurch.Hope was 116 not out and Greaves 55 with the pair putting on 140 for the fifth wicket after the West Indies were in dire straits at 72-4.New Zealand need six more wickets with the new ball six overs away while the West Indies, set a mammoth 531-run target, need a further 319 runs.The tour...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/i31g8ux7wn">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:47:46 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>England win toss, bat in 2nd Test as Australia bring in Neser</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/1pmhw7axw7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/1pmhw7axw7</guid>
      <description>England captain Ben Stokes won the toss and chose to bat in the day-night second Ashes Test as Australia sprang a surprise at the Gabba in Brisbane on Thursday.The hosts go into the match 1-0 up in the five-Test series after thrashing England inside two days in the opener in Perth. Australia&amp;#x27;s regular captain, fast bowler Pat Cummins, was not selected despite rumours he had recovered from a back injury.Off-spinner Nathan Lyon was surprisingly left out of the team in favour of Queensland seamer M...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/1pmhw7axw7">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:58:41 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia race clear of England to seize control of 2nd Test</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/rg8bn7z6kz</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/rg8bn7z6kz</guid>
      <description>A relentless Australia seized a 44-run lead over England in the day-night second Ashes Test in Brisbane on Friday, with aggressive opener Jake Weatherald and Steve Smith leading the charge.By stumps the hosts had not only reeled in England’s first-innings 334 but raced clear, ending a draining day two on 378-6 in front of a big and boisterous crowd at a humid Gabba.A decent lead is shaping as crucial, with the pitch likely to deteriorate in the coming days. “That was a crucial last hour there fo...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/rg8bn7z6kz">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:40:54 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inglis to get nod for 2nd Test as Cummins comeback rumours grow</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/6i3b0y6j0d</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/6i3b0y6j0d</guid>
      <description>Josh Inglis is expected to come into Australia’s batting line-up for the second Ashes Test on Thursday as speculation grows that captain Pat Cummins might make a shock comeback in Brisbane.Travis Head, who made a match-winning century as a makeshift opener in Perth, is set to remain at the top of the order in place of the injured Usman Khawaja, with England-born Inglis slotting into the middle order.Stand-in captain Steve Smith would not confirm the team when he spoke on the eve of the Test or a...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/6i3b0y6j0d">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:57:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh seal Ireland T20 series with dominant win</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gjrjcxjbfz</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gjrjcxjbfz</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh clinched the T20 International series against Ireland in style, having sealed a dominant eight-wicket victory in the third and final game on Tuesday at Bir Shrestha Shaheed Flight Lieutenant Motiur Rahman Stadium in Chattogram.Leg-spinner Rishad Hossain and pacer Mustafizur Rahman claimed three wickets apiece as Bangladesh wrapped up Ireland for 117 in 19.5 overs.Opener Tanzid Hasan Tamim then made the chase a cake-walk, hammering a 36 ball-55 not out, steering Bangladesh to 119-2 in ...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gjrjcxjbfz">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:38:19 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Zealand 231-9 as ‘old school’ West Indies exploit pace-friendly wicket</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/wbxt24q8fy</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/wbxt24q8fy</guid>
      <description>New Zealand reached 231-9 at stumps on a rain-shortened day one of the first Test against the West Indies Tuesday after Justin Greaves triggered a middle-order collapse with the wicket of Kane Williamson.New Zealand tumbled from 94-1 to 148-6 on a bowler-friendly wicket after Williamson was dismissed for 52, his 38th Test half-century.Michael Bracewell and Nathan Smith arrested the slide with a 52-run stand for the seventh wicket. Smith eventually fell for 23 and Bracewell for 47. After Matt Hen...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/wbxt24q8fy">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:01:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weight of history against England in pink-ball Gabba</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/a2dkva0d0t</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/a2dkva0d0t</guid>
      <description>England head into Thursday&amp;#x27;s day-night second Ashes Test against pink-ball masters Australia needing a rare victory at Brisbane&amp;#x27;s Gabba to get back into the five-match series.Travis Head&amp;#x27;s whirlwind century carried Australia to an eight-wicket victory inside two days in Perth as they went 1-0 up.The hosts are again without captain Pat Cummins and fellow quick Josh Hazlewood, leaving swing king Mitchell Starc, who is expected to be a force in humid Brisbane under lights, to carry the attack.Engla...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/a2dkva0d0t">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:59:27 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barca make Atletico comeback to extend Liga lead</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/xwsegbq57g</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/xwsegbq57g</guid>
      <description>Barcelona produced an impressive comeback to beat Atletico Madrid 3-1 on Tuesday and move four points clear at the top of La Liga, with coach Hansi Flick saying his side had taken a step forward after some shaky performances.Alex Baena fired Atletico ahead but Raphinha equalised for the champions before Dani Olmo and Ferran Torres struck to end the visitors’ run of 13 straight league games without defeat.Barca might have been more comfortable had Robert Lewandowski not ballooned a first half pen...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/xwsegbq57g">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:33:06 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Indies win toss, bowl first in opening New Zealand</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/dezd7xdfuk</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/dezd7xdfuk</guid>
      <description>West Indies captain Roston Chase won the toss and elected to bowl in the opening Test against New Zealand at Hagley Oval in Christchurch on Tuesday.Conditions were tailor made for the quick bowlers with the green-tinged wicket complemented by heavy cloud cover.Jayden Seales will spearhead the West Indies attack while Jamaican fast bowler Ojay Shields will make his Test debut at the age of 29.For New Zealand, ranked fifth in the world, it is their first match in the current Test championship cycl...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/dezd7xdfuk">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:21:21 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPL auction: Naim Sheikh the only local player to fetch over 10 million</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/t7npi9ylvo</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/t7npi9ylvo</guid>
      <description>Opener Naim Sheikh has become the only local player to secure a deal worth more than 10 million in the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) players&amp;#x27; auction, held Sunday at a local hotel in the capital.The Chattogram Royals acquired his services for Tk 11 million (Tk 1.1 crore), after winning a competitive four-way bidding war.Naim, who was placed in Category A with a base price of Tk 5 million (Tk 50 lakh), had fierce competition for his signature with Sylhet, Rangpur and Noakhali trying hard, but i...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/t7npi9ylvo">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:17:36 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeba runs to success at the Kathmandu Marathon</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/h195a0vpmt</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/h195a0vpmt</guid>
      <description>Hamida Akter was heading toward Curzon Hall after class to catch the bus home. She noticed a crowd on the gymnasium grounds. Curious about why so many people were running, she asked someone and learned that the inter-hall sports competition was underway.Students were doing laps for the five-kilometre run. She found out that although there were events for women, they didn’t include such long-distance races, the maximum was 400 metres. When she said she wanted to take part in a marathon, someone e...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/h195a0vpmt">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:50:48 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh out to clinch Ireland T20 series</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/f3ci1rl06l</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/f3ci1rl06l</guid>
      <description>In a bid to clinch the T20 International series and cap off the year on a high note, Bangladesh will face Ireland in the third and final T20I on Tuesday at Bir Shrestha Shaheed Flight Lieutenant Motiur Rahman Stadium in Chattogram.The match is scheduled to start at 2pm, and T-sports will broadcast it live.The series is currently tied 1-1, with Bangladesh bouncing back to win the second game by four wickets after Ireland secured a 39-run victory in the opening match. For Bangladesh, this match is...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/f3ci1rl06l">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:34:06 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPL auction: 3 reasons why 9 cricketers were excluded</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/lse6ije0ra</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/lse6ije0ra</guid>
      <description>At last, some of the speculation surrounding this year’s BPL has been cleared. Following an extended investigation by BCB’s anti-corruption consultant Alex Marshall, the BPL Governing Council Saturday published the final player list for today’s auction, excluding nine cricketers suspected of involvement in fixing during the previous BPL. The twelfth BPL auction will be held this afternoon at the Radisson Hotel.A three-member BCB investigation committee led by former Appellate Division judge Mirz...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/lse6ije0ra">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 10:39:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPL auction: How it will work, total costs, and players to watch</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/2ia97t4ckl</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/2ia97t4ckl</guid>
      <description>The auction for the 12th edition of the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) is today, Sunday. Six franchises will buy players at the auction event being held at a hotel in the capital.More than 400 players, local and foreign, have registered for the auction. At least 84 players will be picked, though this number may increase based on the teams’ needs. How many teams are in the auction? Six franchises are participating in this year’s BPL: Dhaka Capitals, Rangpur Riders, Chattogram Royals, Sylhet Tita...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/2ia97t4ckl">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 16:19:50 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh hold their nerve to beat Ireland, level T20I series</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/m0jwuwnj4k</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/m0jwuwnj4k</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh drew level in the T20I series with a composed four-wicket win over Ireland in Chattogram on Saturday night.Bangladesh chased 171 with two balls to spare after a disciplined closing stand from Mohammad Saifuddin and Mahedi Hasan finished the job.Ireland had posted 170 for six, a total built on short, steady contributions rather than one commanding innings. Paul Stirling set the tone with a brisk 29, Tim Tector added 38, and Lorcan Tucker’s 41 from 32 balls helped lift the visitors towa...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/m0jwuwnj4k">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 09:42:23 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kohli stars as India beat South Africa</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/scfv1v37ib</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/scfv1v37ib</guid>
      <description>Star batsman Virat Kohli hit a record-extending 52nd one-day century to set up India’s 17-run win over a spirited South Africa in the first match on Sunday.Kohli’s 135 came off 120 balls and he shared a second-wicket partnership of 136 with fellow stalwart Rohit Sharma to set India on course for 349-8 in the eastern city of Ranchi.Corbin Bosch made a valiant 67 off 51 balls as South Africa fought until almost the end. Entering the 50th over, the visitors needed 18 for victory with one wicket lef...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/scfv1v37ib">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 23:08:16 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Players accused of fixing excluded from final BPL auction list</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gcvftdqsuo</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gcvftdqsuo</guid>
      <description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has decided to exclude cricketers accused of fixing in the BPL auction.Although the BCB has not officially announced their names, seven local players who were on the preliminary list are being dropped from the final BPL auction list.They are: Anamul Haque, Mosaddek Hossain, Alauddin Babu, Sanjamul Islam, Mizanur Rahman, Nihaduzzaman, and Shafiul Islam.The BCB has not officially stated whether they were excluded specifically because of allegations of involvement...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gcvftdqsuo">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 17:58:58 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estevao dazzles as rampant Chelsea thrash 10-man Barca 3-0</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/5w6vu431ei</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/5w6vu431ei</guid>
      <description>Estevao scored a breathtaking solo Champions League goal to win the battle of the teenage prodigies against Lamine Yamal on Tuesday as Chelsea humbled 10-man Barcelona 3-0.The two 18-year-olds were the focus of attention in the build-up to the game at Stamford Bridge, with Chelsea boss Enzo Maresca urging his player to ignore the comparisons.Estevao&amp;#x27;s moment of magic came 10 minutes after half time when he received the ball on the right before beating two defenders and lashing it into the roof o...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/5w6vu431ei">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:45:43 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa condemn India to biggest home Test loss for series sweep</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/jetk92fvky</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/jetk92fvky</guid>
      <description>Spinner Simon Harmer took six wickets as South Africa romped to victory by 408 runs in the second Test for their first series win in India in 25 years on Wednesday.World Test champions South Africa bowled out a dismal India for 140 in a mammoth chase of 549 on day five in Guwahati for a 2-0 Test sweep.It is India&amp;#x27;s biggest defeat at home by runs and a fifth loss in seven home Tests, having been whitewashed 3-0 by New Zealand last year.Off-spinner Harmer, 36, returned figures of 6-37 as South Afr...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/jetk92fvky">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:04:48 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ireland outclass Bangladesh to take lead in T20I series</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/csl43evld5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/csl43evld5</guid>
      <description>Ireland seized the opening T20I with a big 39-run win over Bangladesh on Thursday night in Chattogram.Ireland successfully defended 181 with discipline and composure as the hosts faltered in a chase that never settled.Towhid Hridoy hit 83 not-out for Bangladesh, but other batters failed to cope up. Asked to bat first, Ireland delivered a polished performance built around Harry Tector’s assured 69* off 45 balls—a knock of clean timing and smart acceleration.Tim Tector’s brisk 32 and a late surge ...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/csl43evld5">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:46:52 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jansen takes six as South Africa close on historic Test series win</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/b7v4i84aay</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/b7v4i84aay</guid>
      <description>Towering pace spearhead Marco Jansen took six wickets to put South Africa in sight of a first Test series win in India in 25 years after bundling out the hosts for 201 in the second match today, Monday.Replying to South Africa&amp;#x27;s 489, India were 288 behind in their first innings but the tourists did not enforce the follow-on and decided to bat again on day three in Guwahati.After winning the first Test in the two-match series in Kolkata, South Africa are closing on a first series win in India sin...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/b7v4i84aay">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:04:47 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSC orders not to use national team players in election campaign</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/local-sports/1sikcgvqjl</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/local-sports/1sikcgvqjl</guid>
      <description>The National Sports Council (NSC) has ordered relevant sports federations, associations, and all concerned parties not to use national team players for election campaigns or any political purpose.Although national players were seen participating in campaign activities in previous elections, the NSC has issued this directive in advance ahead of the upcoming polls.In a letter signed by NSC director Mohammad Aminul Ehsan, it stated, “National team players are a national asset and a symbol of unity ...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/local-sports/1sikcgvqjl">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:38:24 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stubbs hits 94 as South Africa set India mammoth 549 target</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/y6s4qj6ni1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/y6s4qj6ni1</guid>
      <description>Tristan Stubbs made 94 as South Africa declared their second innings on 260-5 to set India a record victory target of 549 and close in on a series win in the second Test on Tuesday.World Test champions South Africa lead the two-match series 1-0 and even a draw in Guwahati would seal their first series win in India since 2000.India suffered their fourth defeat in six home Tests in the opener in Kolkata and the hosts need to bat for more than three sessions to avoid another loss.The highest succes...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/y6s4qj6ni1">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:09:12 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muthusamy, Jansen put South Africa on top of India</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/sg5oh9s0c1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/sg5oh9s0c1</guid>
      <description>Senuran Muthusamy struck his first Test century and Marco Jansen hammered 93 to guide South Africa to a commanding 489 all out on day two of the second match against India on Sunday.The left-handed Muthusamy made 109 and put on 97 runs for the eighth wicket with Jansen, who was the last wicket to fall in the final session in Guwahati.“First innings runs in the sub-continent are vital,” Muthusamy told reporters. “So, yeah, it was just really, really awesome experience out there. And it was just a...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/sg5oh9s0c1">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 18:47:11 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Messi magic as Miami thrash Cincinnati, face NYCFC next</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/bpod4bkp3w</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/bpod4bkp3w</guid>
      <description>Lionel Messi produced a vintage performance as Inter Miami stayed on course for their first MLS Cup final appearance with a 4-0 rout of FC Cincinnati on Sunday.Argentine superstar Messi scored once and provided the assists for all of Inter&amp;#x27;s other goals, with Tadeo Allende scoring twice and Mateo Silvetti adding the other to send Miami into next Saturday&amp;#x27;s Eastern Conference championship.Inter Miami will play host to New York City FC to decide a berth in the MLS Cup final after visiting City ups...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/bpod4bkp3w">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:04:53 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh crush Ireland by 217 runs to complete series sweep</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/cildywdc7v</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/cildywdc7v</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh cruised to a dominant 217-run victory over Ireland in the second and final Test, sealing a 2-0 series sweep after a commanding all-round display at the Sher-e-Bangla National Cricket Stadium today, Sunday.The inevitable came after a brief spell of tension after Curstis Campher put on a staunch resistance, delaying Bangladesh’s push for a victory.He kept the side unscathed throughout the morning session for an unlikely victory. However, Hasan Murad took the last two wickets in consecut...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/cildywdc7v">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 18:42:15 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Campher resistance delays Bangladesh&amp;#x27;s victory</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/qgcmkop952</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/qgcmkop952</guid>
      <description>Curtis Campher put on a staunch resistance to keep Bangladesh waiting for victory in the second and final Test, as Ireland battled through the extended morning session on Day 5 at Sher-e-Bangla National Cricket Stadium today.Chasing an improbable 509 for victory, Ireland went to lunch at 263-8, still 246 runs away from an unlikely win.Campher remained the biggest obstacle for Bangladesh, batting through the entire session to reach an unbeaten 63. He will resume after the interval alongside Gavin...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/qgcmkop952">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:06:36 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh secure massive lead after Taijul becomes Tigers’ highest wicket taker in Test</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/obi4ayv3n3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/obi4ayv3n3</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh secured a lead of 367 runs at the end of the third day of the Dhaka Test against Ireland on Friday.After posting 476 in the first innings, Bangladesh finished the third day with 156 for one, with Shadman Islam and Mominul Haque remaining unbeaten on 69 not out and 19, respectively.Earlier, Ireland posted 265 against tigers’ first innings and fell behind.Taijul bags 4 as Bangladesh bowl Ireland out for 265 to secure big leadTaijul Islam took four wickets for the team, and with these fo...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/obi4ayv3n3">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 13:42:01 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Head&amp;#x27;s 69-ball ton powers Australia to victory in Ashes opener</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/iow48jojxl</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/iow48jojxl</guid>
      <description>Makeshift opener Travis Head smacked an explosive 69-ball century to power Australia to victory in a high-octane first Ashes Test on Saturday as England meekly surrendered in the Perth Stadium cauldron.Chasing 205 to win, Head slammed 123 as the hosts romped home on day two by eight wickets in an electric start to the five-match series. Marnus Labuschagne was not-out 51 and Steve Smith on two.&amp;quot;Wow, what a couple of days. It&amp;#x27;s been unbelievable,&amp;quot; said Head. &amp;quot;The emotions are pretty high.&amp;quot;They (En...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/iow48jojxl">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 17:37:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh A beat India A to confirm berth in final</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/niqq3zmd8n</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/niqq3zmd8n</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh A confirmed their place in the final of the Asia Cup Rising Stars after edging India A in a thrilling semi-final that went down to a nerve-wracking Super Over at Doha in Qatar today, Friday.Bangladesh A posted a formidable 194-6 in their stipulated 20 overs and appeared well on course for victory in regulation time, having taken wickets at regular intervals. However, a blunder on the final ball dragged the game into a Super Over. India’s Harsh Dubey, needing four runs off the last del...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/niqq3zmd8n">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:55:24 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>England in charge after dismissing Australia for 132 in Ashes opener</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/znqsc4tvp1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/znqsc4tvp1</guid>
      <description>England dismissed Australia for 132 in their first innings on Saturday to take charge of the first Ashes Test in Perth, with the hosts trailing by 40 runs on an overcast day two.An explosive opening day of searing pace saw an astonishing 19 wickets tumble.Australia added just nine runs to their paltry overnight 123-9 before Nathan Lyon was removed by Brydon Carse for four. Inspirational skipper Ben Stokes ended with 5-23 while Carse chipped in with 3-45 and Jofra Archer 2-11.It culminated a stun...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/znqsc4tvp1">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:25:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41st BCS applications break previous records</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/41st-BCS-applications-break-record-previous</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/41st-BCS-applications-break-record-previous</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC) has received a record number of applications from aspirants willing to get government lucrative jobs through the 41st BCS examination. BPSC examination controller Nesaruddin said that the total number of applicants in the 41st BCS exam is 475,000 and it is the highest in the history of Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) exams. A total of 412,000 aspirants applied for the 40th BCS exam in 2018. On 27 November 2019, the BPSC floated the circular of the 41st ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/41st-BCS-applications-break-record-previous">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:02:58 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physicians can apply for 39th special BCS test from 10 Apr</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Physicians-can-apply-for-39th-special-BCS-test</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Physicians-can-apply-for-39th-special-BCS-test</guid>
      <description>Job seekers can apply for appearing in the 39th special Bangladesh Civil Service recruitment test from 10 to 30 April as the Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC) has published a circular seeking application against 4,792 posts of physicians. The circular was published on Sunday afternoon, said a press release. According to the health ministry, a total of 4,542 assistant surgeons and 250 dental surgeons will be recruited through the 39th BCS exam. The age limit for the candidates is betwee...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Physicians-can-apply-for-39th-special-BCS-test">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 20:01:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resistance anthem rocks Iraq</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Resistance-anthem-rocks-Iraq</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Resistance-anthem-rocks-Iraq</guid>
      <description>While Baghdad anti-regime protesters have clashed with riot police, their supporters in Mosul are using art to fight for change, with a new take on the resistance anthem &amp;quot;Bella Ciao&amp;quot;. In a viral music video clip, the World War II-era Italian anti-fascist song has been tweaked to &amp;quot;Blaya Chara&amp;quot; -- meaning &amp;quot;no way out&amp;quot; in Iraqi dialect. It captures the fatalistic sentiment many young Iraqis hold towards their violence-torn homeland. &amp;quot;I don&amp;#x27;t have heating, not a cent to spend. Why would I even study...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Resistance-anthem-rocks-Iraq">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 10:23:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41th BCS: Circular to recruit 2,166 published</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/41th-BCS-Circular-to-recruit-2-166-published</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/41th-BCS-Circular-to-recruit-2-166-published</guid>
      <description>The Bangladesh Public Service Commission (PSC) has published the 41th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) circular seeking applications for 2,166 posts, reports UNB. The circular was published on the PSC website on Wednesday noon. It said the application process will begin at 10:00am on 5 December and end at 6:00pm on 4 January. The details of the application process are available on the PSC website: http://www.bpsc.gov.bd.</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/41th-BCS-Circular-to-recruit-2-166-published">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 17:03:25 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40th BCS written exams begin 4 Jan</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/40th-BCS-written-exams-begin-4-Jan</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/40th-BCS-written-exams-begin-4-Jan</guid>
      <description>The written test of 40th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) examinations will begin from 4 January 2020. The decision was taken at a special meeting of Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPCS) on Tuesday. PSC public relations officer Israt Sharmin confirmed this to Prothom Alo. According to the meeting sources, the compulsory subjects will be held between 4 and 8 January. The date of other examinations will be announced later. The preliminary test for 40th BCS was held on 3 May 2019. As many as 3...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/40th-BCS-written-exams-begin-4-Jan">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 18:19:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10-day ‘Bangla Natya Utsab’ begins Monday</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/10-day-‘Bangla-Natya-Utsab’-begins-Monday</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/10-day-‘Bangla-Natya-Utsab’-begins-Monday</guid>
      <description>A 10-day drama festival will be kicked off in the capital on Monday, aiming to present Bangla drama as a linkage between the Bangla-speaking people and make theatre an awareness-raising medium to influence social and cultural landscapes. The gala titled ‘Bangla Natya Utsab’ is being organised to celebrate with festivities the three-era completion of Mahakal Natya Sampraday, a theatre circle, reports BSS. The festival will screen Bangla dramas from Bangladesh and three other Bangla-speaking state...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/10-day-‘Bangla-Natya-Utsab’-begins-Monday">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 11:59:34 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41st BCS circular soon</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Circular-for-41st-BCS-soon</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Circular-for-41st-BCS-soon</guid>
      <description>The circular of the 41st Bangladesh Civil Service jobs will be published soon. Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC) said the next BCS will be in general category against 2,135 positions. BPSC and public administration ministry sources said the PSC has received directives to recruit for the vacant positions. The PSC is also set to publish the job circular, the sources added. PSC chairman Mohammad Sadiq said, “We have decided to publish a circular of 41st BCS. The circular will published on...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Circular-for-41st-BCS-soon">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 15:40:10 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selim Al Deen Utsab begins at Shilpakala Academy</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Selim-Al-Deen-Utsab-‘19-begins-at-Shilpakala</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Selim-Al-Deen-Utsab-‘19-begins-at-Shilpakala</guid>
      <description>The three-day long Selim Al Deen Utsab-2019 and the 8th national council of Bangladesh Gram Theatre began at Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy in the capital on Friday.State minister for cultural affairs KM Khalid inaugurated the festival, jointly organised by Bangladesh Gram Theatre and Dhaka Theatre, reports UNB.At the beginning of the programme, the guests placed wreaths at the portraits of the father of the nation Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, Nobel Laureate Rabindranath Tagore, national po...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Selim-Al-Deen-Utsab-‘19-begins-at-Shilpakala">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 10:54:52 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agricultural extension department to recruit 1357</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Agricultural-extension-department-to-recruit-1357</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Agricultural-extension-department-to-recruit-1357</guid>
      <description>The government’s Department of Agricultural Extension will recruit 1,357 people in different positions. Any Bangladeshi national with prescribed qualifications can apply for the jobs. The application opened at 10:00am on 7 August this year and will be closed at 5:00pm on 6 September. The job seekers have been asked to apply through http://dae.teletalk.com.bd.</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Agricultural-extension-department-to-recruit-1357">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 20:07:17 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dutch-Bangla Bank to recruit probationary officers</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Dutch-Bangla-Bank-to-recruit-probationary-officers</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Dutch-Bangla-Bank-to-recruit-probationary-officers</guid>
      <description>Dutch-Bangla Bank Limited (DBBL), one of the private banks in the country, will recruit probationary officers.The applicants must have a bachelor degree with at least three first classes or equivalent CGPA (MBA from BIBM, BSc Engineering from BUET/RUET/KUET/CUET and BBA from IBA of Dhaka University).Third class at any level of the previous examinations will not be acceptable.The age limit is 30 for general applicants and 32 years for those with Freedom Fighter quota. The job seekers must have sk...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Dutch-Bangla-Bank-to-recruit-probationary-officers">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 20:02:43 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>99pc educated youths seek govt jobs: Survey</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/99pc-educated-youths-seek-govt-jobs-Survey</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/99pc-educated-youths-seek-govt-jobs-Survey</guid>
      <description>Almost all educated youths of the country seek government jobs, according to a new survey. About 99 per cent educated youths of the country seek government jobs and of them, 57 per cent is female and 42 per cent male, the survey shows. BRAC, the BRAC Institute of Governance and Development (BIGC) and BRAC University jointly conducted the BRAC Youth Survey-2018. The findings of the survey were revealed at a city hotel today. State Minister for Sports and Youths? Zahid Ahsan Rasel, Secretary inCha...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/99pc-educated-youths-seek-govt-jobs-Survey">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:21:56 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BCS candidates increasing steadily</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BCS-candidates-increasing-steadily</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BCS-candidates-increasing-steadily</guid>
      <description>The number of job seekers for cadre service (class one gazetted officer in government service) has been increasing gradually, according to statistics of Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC). A total of 115,164 candidates applied for the 28th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) examinations in 2008 while a total of 412,000 applied for the 40th BCS examinations in 2018. Former PCS chairman Saadat Husain said interest in BCS is increasing for three reasons. The number of youth has increased in th...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BCS-candidates-increasing-steadily">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 18:15:41 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPSC to recruit 76 officials</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BPSC-to-recruit-76-officials</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BPSC-to-recruit-76-officials</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC) has published a job circular to recruit 76 officials for under grades of 9th, 10th and 11th. The application process began on 31 July and will continue till 6:00pm on 5 September 2019. Any Bangladeshi national with prescribed qualifications can apply for the posts. The posts include a junior instructor (salary Tk 22,000-Tk 53,000), two assistant programmers (salary Tk 22,000-Tk 53,000), a nutrition development officer (salary Tk 22,000-Tk 53,000), an a...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BPSC-to-recruit-76-officials">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 08:45:48 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choir, Broadway casts perform in the street during NY blackout</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/New-York-moments-choir-Broadway-casts-perform-in</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/New-York-moments-choir-Broadway-casts-perform-in</guid>
      <description>When a massive blackout plunged much of Manhattan into darkness on Saturday evening, a choir and the casts of Broadway musicals entertained tourists with impromptu performances in the street. The outages struck at around 7:00pm (2300 GMT), just as many shows were starting at theaters in Midtown and at the Lincoln Center plaza on New York City&amp;#x27;s Upper West Side. With subway stations and traffic lights suddenly dark, thousands of people spilled outside on a hot summer&amp;#x27;s night. Some were surprised ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/New-York-moments-choir-Broadway-casts-perform-in">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 13:39:48 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Names of Shilpakala Padak-2018 recipients announced</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Names-of-Shilpakala-Padak-2018-recipients</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Names-of-Shilpakala-Padak-2018-recipients</guid>
      <description>The names of seven personalities, who will receive &amp;#x27;Shilpakala Padak-2018&amp;#x27; for their contributions to their respective fields, were announced on Tuesday, reports news agency UNB. They are -- Gouro Gopal Haldar (vocal), Sunil Chandra Das (instrumental), M Hamid (dramatics), Mina Barua (folklore), Alokesh Ghosh (fine arts), Shukla Sarkar (dance) and Jayanta Chattopadhyay (recitation). Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy (BSA) director Liaquat Ali Lucky announced the names at a press conference. Presiden...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Names-of-Shilpakala-Padak-2018-recipients">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 20:26:29 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman visits ailing mother Khaleda Zia at hospital</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/8f3xz8dd0z</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/8f3xz8dd0z</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman now stays beside ailing mother and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka. He reached the hospital at around 6pm after attending a mammoth public gathering at 36 Expressway (300-Foot Road) to welcome him on his historic homecoming from London.Tarique Rahman returned home after a long 17 years in exile in the UK. He arrived at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport here around 11.40am by a regular Bim...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/8f3xz8dd0z">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 18:28:15 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law and order must be maintained at any cost: Tarique Rahman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/endkk3hucu</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/endkk3hucu</guid>
      <description>Returning to the country after nearly a decade and a half in exile, BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has pledged to maintain law and order at any cost. At the same time, he called on people to remain calm in the face of any provocation.At a time when uncertainty and anxiety have spread among the public due to various criminal activities, including mob attacks, about a year and a half after the fall of the Awami League government through a mass uprising, Tarique Rahman made this pledge upon his...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/endkk3hucu">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:09:46 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osman Hadi murder: Motorcyclist Alamgir&amp;#x27;s &amp;#x27;associate&amp;#x27; arrested with weapons</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/punwyugzxa</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/punwyugzxa</guid>
      <description>Police have arrested a youth along with a foreign pistol and ammunition from the Adabar area of the capital.The arrested man, Himon Rahman Shikdar, 32, is an associate of Alamgir Sheikh—one of the main accused in the murder case of martyr Sharif Osman bin Hadi, police said.According to police, Himon is an activist of the Adabar thana Jubo League. He was arrested yesterday, Wednesday. Police say he was planning subversive activities along with his associates.Additional Deputy Commissioner of the ...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/punwyugzxa">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:30:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCP forming alliance with Jamaat, claims Abdul Qader</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/wbrknhqdjg</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/wbrknhqdjg</guid>
      <description>Abdul Qader, one of the leaders of the July uprising and a former coordinator of the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement, has claimed that the National Citizen Party (NCP) is moving toward an electoral seat-sharing arrangement with Jamaat-e-Islami.In a Facebook post on Thursday morning, Abdul Qader said that if everything goes according to plan, the announcement of this alliance may come on Friday.No immediate response from the NCP was available regarding the matter. After Abdul Qader’s post, c...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/wbrknhqdjg">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:48:30 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman speaks with chief adviser Yunus after arriving in Dhaka</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/ki393fxiu2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/ki393fxiu2</guid>
      <description>BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman spoke by phone with Professor Muhammad Yunus, chief adviser of the interim government, shortly after arriving in Dhaka on Thursday.Tarique made the call from the VIP lounge of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport, according to a post on BNP’s media cell verified Facebook page at 12:26 pm.The post included a video showing Tarique seated on a sofa while speaking on the phone. After 17 years abroad, Tarique returned to Bangladesh today, accompanied by his wife Z...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/ki393fxiu2">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 14:36:25 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I have a plan: Tarique Rahman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/8pc9vh0tx2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/8pc9vh0tx2</guid>
      <description>The motorcade carrying Tarique Rahman reached the public reception venue in Purbachal of the capital from Shahjalal International Airport in a bus decorated in red and green.At around 3:51pm, Tarique Rahman took the stage. He began his speech at 3:57pm. He opened by saying, “Dear Bangladesh.” BNP leaders were with him. After getting on the stage, Tarique Rahman waved to the leaders and activists.BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir welcomed Tarique Rahman on the stage.“Respected eld...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/8pc9vh0tx2">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 18:26:26 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will India move away from its reliance on Awami League?</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/vtsex8hesf</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/vtsex8hesf</guid>
      <description>Tensions have persisted in Bangladesh–India bilateral relations for the past 16 months. Over the last 10 days, they have deepened into a serious crisis. The two countries have continued summoning each other’s diplomats and issuing counter-statements.At the same time, Hindutva groups have staged protests targeting Bangladesh missions in Delhi, Kolkata, Mumbai and Agartala, leading to clashes with law enforcement agencies.Citing security concerns, Dhaka has suspended visa services in India at leas...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/vtsex8hesf">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 14:19:38 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman’s pet cat ‘Jebu’ returns to country with him</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/n5mpdjkdxl</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/n5mpdjkdxl</guid>
      <description>‘Jebu’ is the pet cat of the family of BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman. The cat also arrived in Dhaka today, Thursday, from London in the United Kingdom along with members of Tarique Rahman’s family.After 12:00 pm today, the BNP’s verified Facebook page announced Jebu’s return to the country, sharing photographs alongside the post. The caption read, ‘Jebu returns to country.’ A short while earlier, the flight carrying Tarique Rahman landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka. H...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/n5mpdjkdxl">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:57:30 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman’s return will fill the political vacuum: Shafiqul Alam</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/jqmcrwj50j</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/jqmcrwj50j</guid>
      <description>Chief adviser’s press secretary Shafiqul Alam believes that Tarique Rahman’s arrival will fill a political vacuum in Bangladesh. He said there is indeed a certain political vacuum in the country, and Tarique Rahman’s arrival will fill it.He made the remarks in response to a query from newspersons after visiting the Holy Rosary Church in Tejgaon, Dhaka, today Thursday, to exchange Christmas greetings with members of the Christian community. Chief adviser’s special assistant Khoda Baksh Chowdhury ...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/jqmcrwj50j">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:49:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hadi murder case: Jubo League leader Taizul helped the killer flee</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/ph3zhpiuuj</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/ph3zhpiuuj</guid>
      <description>The police have identified two individuals who helped Faisal Karim Masud, the main accused in the murder of Inqilab Moncho convenor Sharif Osman Hadi, and his accomplice Alamgir Sheikh, flee to India.One of them has been arrested by the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DB). The arrested individual is Aminul Islam, the brother-in-law of a Jubo League leader. With this arrest, police and RAB have now detained 11 people in connection with Hadi’s murder.Sources involved in the investigation said law enfor...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/ph3zhpiuuj">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:27:46 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCP central leader resigns, expresses support for Tarique Rahman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/m0h3lz6ur1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/m0h3lz6ur1</guid>
      <description>Mir Arshadul Haque, joint secretary of the central committee of the National Citizen Party (NCP), has left the party, accusing it of failing to fulfil the promise of the July mass uprising. At the same time, he has expressed his support for BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman.Mir Arshadul Haque held multiple positions in the NCP, including central joint secretary, member of the executive council, member of the media cell and disciplinary committee, head of the environment cell, and chief coordina...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/m0h3lz6ur1">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:50:53 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman returns to Bangladesh after 17 years</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/8lhxfu7b04</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/8lhxfu7b04</guid>
      <description>BNP’s acting chairman Tarique Rahman has arrived in Bangladeshi after 17 years. Today, Thursday, at 9:56 am, the Bangladesh Biman flight carrying Tarique Rahman landed at Osmani International Airport in Sylhet.Accompanying him are his wife Zubaida Rahman and daughter Zaima Rahman. After the stopover in Sylhet, Tarique Rahman will proceed directly to Dhaka. Meanwhile, a large number of BNP leaders and activists gathered early at the venue of the public reception to welcome the acting chairman’s r...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/8lhxfu7b04">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:25:17 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman’s Facebook posts on way back to Bangladesh: What he wrote</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/imo73idw43</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/imo73idw43</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) acting chairman Tarique Rahman made several posts on his verified Facebook page on his way back to the country from London, United Kingdom.At 5:15 am on 25 December, he made his first post titled “Return.” Tarique Rahman also attached a photo of himself with the post. The photo shows Tarique Rahman seated on the airplane, reading a document bearing the name and logo of Biman Bangladesh Airlines. The document relates to a “Medical Certificate for Air Travel.”Tar...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/imo73idw43">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:52:48 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>