<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BD News - BD Pratidin</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EhsanulHaqueSiam/BDNewsPaperScraper</link>
    <description>Latest news from Bangladeshi newspapers (23 articles)</description>
    <language>en-bd</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:57:17 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>BDNewsPaperScraper RSS Generator</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique calls CA Yunus, expresses gratitude</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53463</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53463</guid>
      <description>Immediately after landing in Dhaka, BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman made a phone call to Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus from the airport to express his gratitude. A video of the phone conversation has been shared on Tarique Rahman’s official Facebook page. In the video, Tarique Rahman is heard saying: &amp;quot;On behalf of myself and my family, I want to thank you. You have made various arrangements, especially for my security. And we are… thank you so much… thank you so much for all the arrangements...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53463">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold wave continues, affecting normal life in northern region</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53498</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53498</guid>
      <description>Although the minimum temperatures remained mostly unchanged and maximum temperatures increased slightly, the mild cold wave blowing over the northern region continued affecting the normal life for the third consecutive day on Thursday. The sky remained partly cloudy and misty till noon with cold winds blowing from the west and northwest. The sufferings of the poor people living in the riverbank and char areas of the Brahmaputra basin remained deplorable today as it has been for the past few days...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53498">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>England dominate as Australia bowled out for 152 in 4th Ashes Test</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/26/53524</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/26/53524</guid>
      <description>England tore through the Australian batting line-up to bowl the hosts out for just 152 on day one of the fourth Ashes Test at the Melbourne Cricket Ground, taking complete control on a green, bowler-friendly track, reports AFP. Skipper Ben Stokes won the toss and sent Australia in under overcast skies. Openers Travis Head and Jake Weatherald fell for 12 and 10, while Marnus Labuschagne managed only six, as Gus Atkinson and Josh Tongue exploited early movement. Steve Smith tried to stabilize the ...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/26/53524">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique’s motorcade off to Gulshan</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53497</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53497</guid>
      <description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman left for his Gulshan residence after visiting his mother, former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia, who is undergoing treatment at Evercare Hospital in Bashundhara. The bus carrying him left Evercare Hospital at around 7:30 pm on Thursday (December 25). Earlier, Tarique Rahman visited the hospital at around 5:45 pm. When the bus carrying him reached the hospital gate, he got off and walked inside. Top party leaders accompanied him at the time. Tarique Rahman’s w...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/national/2025/12/25/53497">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salah scores goal as Egypt rally to win against Zimbabwe</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/23/53334</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/23/53334</guid>
      <description>Mohamed Salah snatched a dramatic stoppage-time winner as Egypt came from behind to beat Zimbabwe 2-1 in their first fixture at the Africa Cup of Nations (AFCON) finals in Morocco on Monday. Egypt’s captain, starting his first game after four successive matches ⁠on the bench at Liverpool, fired home a left-footed effort in the 91st minute to earn the seven-time champions a ​late victory after Zimbabwe had stunned them by going ahead in the first half, reports AL Jazeera. Egypt laid an early ‍sie...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/23/53334">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajshahi hand captaincy to Shanto ahead of BPL</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/22/53270</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/22/53270</guid>
      <description>Najmul Hossain Shanto will lead Rajshahi Warriors in the upcoming Bangladesh Premier League, with the franchise confirming his captaincy on Monday, reports the Daily Sun. The Rajshahi Warriors’ media group shared the information. Rajshahi have placed their trust in the national Test captain, who has previously led Bangladesh in all three formats, despite having several experienced options in the side. The squad features players like Mushfiqur Rahim and Akbar Ali. However, the franchise opted to ...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/22/53270">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Awesome’ Australia dominate to clinch Ashes as England left hurting</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53224</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53224</guid>
      <description>Australia captain Pat Cummins described the moment as “pretty awesome” on Sunday after his dominant side wrapped up the Ashes with victory in the third Test in Adelaide, sealing the series in just 11 days of play despite a defiant final-day stand from England’s tail, reports AFP. Chasing a record 435 to win, England’s last four wickets added a stubborn 145 runs before they were finally dismissed for 352, handing Australia an 82-run victory and ensuring the famous urn remained in Australian hands...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53224">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>England beaten to lose another Ashes in Australia</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53206</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53206</guid>
      <description>England&amp;#x27;s Bazball project is in tatters as yet another Ashes in Australia was lost in three Tests, reports BBC. The visiting team were defeated by 82 runs on the fifth day of the third Test in Adelaide to go 3-0 down and extend a winless run in this country to 18 matches. Australia were delayed by a 40-minute rain shower, England pair Jamie Smith and Will Jacks, and a hamstring injury to spinner Nathan Lyon. Smith had 60 when he miscued Mitchell Starc. Jacks battled past lunch for his 47 then ed...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53206">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jumar–Urmi fall in final, secure historic silver</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53182</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53182</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh’s mixed doubles pair Al Amin Jumar and Urmi Akter made history by reaching the final of an international badminton tournament for the first time, winning the silver medal at the Yonex-Sunrise Bangladesh International Challenge 2025, reports the Daily Sun. In the mixed doubles final, the Bangladeshi duo faced Malaysia’s Datu Anif and Clarissa San. Jumar and Urmi fought hard in the opening game but were unable to sustain the pressure in the later stages, eventually losing the match 27–2...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53182">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mbappé matches Ronaldo’s Real Madrid record with 59 goals in a calendar year</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53191</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53191</guid>
      <description>Kylian Mbappé equaled a long-standing Real Madrid record on Saturday after scoring his 59th goal of 2025, matching Cristiano Ronaldo’s mark for the most goals in a single year for the club, reports UNB. The French forward sealed Madrid’s 2-0 victory over Sevilla with a late penalty, converting from the spot four minutes from time in the team’s final match of the year. The goal came just in time, as the milestone appeared to be slipping away. Celebrating his 27th birthday, Mbappé reached the same...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/21/53191">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustafizur trumps Taskin to lead Dubai to win in ILT20</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53180</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53180</guid>
      <description>On a day when two Bangladesh pace spearhead faced off in International League T20 (ILT20) in Dubai, Mustafizur Rahman prevailed to lead his side Dubai Capitals to victory, ruining the valiant effort of his compatriot and new ball partner Taskin Ahmed, reports BSS. Mustafizur’s 2-13 became more valuable in his Dubai’s 63-run victory over Sharjah Warriors, who saw Taskin battle lonely for them. Taskin grabbed 3-40 to be the pick of the bowler for Sharjah but despite his superb performance, Dubai p...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53180">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BPL tickets for Sylhet phase on sale from Sunday, prices start at Tk200</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53173</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53173</guid>
      <description>Tickets for the Sylhet phase of the 12th edition of the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) will go on sale from Sunday, reports the Daily Sun. The reports confirmed this update, citing Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) media release. The BPL is set to get underway on Friday at the Sylhet International Cricket Stadium, marking the start of another highly anticipated season of the country’s premier T20 tournament. According to a media release, the ticketing process will be conducted entirely online, wit...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53173">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gill misses out on India&amp;#x27;s T20 World Cup squad</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53166</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53166</guid>
      <description>Defending champions and co-hosts India have named their squad for the ICC Men’s T20 World Cup 2026, set to begin on February 7. The hosts enter the tournament aiming to clinch a record third title, ICC reports. Suryakumar Yadav is set to lead India in his first-ever ICC tournament as captain, with Axar Patel named as his deputy in the absence of star batter Shubman Gill, who was dropped after lean performances upon his return to the T20I setup in September. Along with Gill, Jitesh Sharma, who ha...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53166">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rajshahi first to begin BPL preparations, but in national kit</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53142</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53142</guid>
      <description>Rajshahi Warriors became the first franchise to begin preparations for the upcoming Bangladesh Premier League, holding their opening practice session on Saturday at the Mirpur Academy Ground. The session took an unusual yet eye-catching turn as the players initially trained wearing Bangladesh national team practice kits instead of their franchise colours. The sight caused brief confusion among onlookers before it was clarified that the Rajshahi Warriors’ official kits had yet to arrive at the ve...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/20/53142">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guardiola dismisses Manchester City exit talk ahead of West Ham clash</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53118</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53118</guid>
      <description>Manchester City boss Pep Guardiola dismissed speculation over his future at the club, insisting contract talks are not on the agenda despite rumours he could leave at the end of the season, but added his side were not yet good enough to win the title. While Guardiola&amp;#x27;s team, who host lowly West Ham United on Saturday, could overtake Arsenal for top spot in the Premier League this weekend, the Spaniard&amp;#x27;s job status was the hot topic at his pre-game press conference on Friday. &amp;quot;I always get asked ...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53118">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jumar–Urmi create history by reaching mixed doubles final</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53117</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53117</guid>
      <description>Al Amin Jumar and Urmi Akter continued to deliver good news for Bangladesh, lighting up the night of the weekend just as they had done in the morning. The pair created history in Bangladeshi badminton by reaching the final of the mixed doubles event at the Yonex-Sunrise Bangladesh International Challenge, reports the Daily Sun. Earlier in the day, Jumar and Urmi had already secured at least a bronze medal, but by nightfall, they went one step further, ensuring a place in the final. This marks th...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53117">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan end Bangladesh’s dream with dominant eight-wicket win</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53115</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53115</guid>
      <description>Pakistan Under-19 brought an end to Bangladesh’s quest for a third consecutive title with a commanding eight-wicket victory in the rain-affected semifinal of the U-19 Asia Cup at The Sevens Stadium in Dubai on Friday. Asked to bat first in the curtailed 27-over contest, Bangladesh struggled from the outset and were bowled out for 121 with three balls remaining. The innings never gathered momentum after opener Rifat Beg fell for 14 off 16 balls with 24 runs on the board. Fellow opener and in-form...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53115">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morocco beat Jordan 3-2 after extra time to clinch Arab Cup</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53103</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53103</guid>
      <description>Morocco defeated Jordan 3-2 after extra time to claim the Arab Cup on Thursday, reports Reuters. Abderrazzaq Hamed Allah scored two goals following a stunning long-range strike from Oussama Tannane. Morocco opened the scoring after four minutes when Tannane&amp;#x27;s audacious shot from the centre circle caught advancing goalkeeper Yazeed Abulaila off guard. Jordan, set to make their World Cup debut in 2026, hit back with a second-half double from Ali Olwan&amp;#x27;s header and penalty in the 48th and 68th minu...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/19/53103">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘It was just a misunderstanding’</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53494</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53494</guid>
      <description>Former Bangladesh captain Khaled Mahmud Sujon has played down his dramatic walkout from Noakhali Express’s training session, calling the episode “just a misunderstanding” ahead of the Bangladesh Premier League, reports the Daily Sun. Sujon left the Sylhet International Cricket Stadium on Thursday, initially saying he would not continue in the BPL after becoming frustrated with training arrangements and equipment shortages. “It’s just a misunderstanding. It maybe happened in the heat of the momen...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53494">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shanto prioritises Rajshahi impact with T20 World Cup in sight</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53475</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53475</guid>
      <description>Najmul Hossain Shanto has made no secret of his priorities as he prepares to lead Rajshahi, with the T20 World Cup firmly in his sights, reports the Daily Sun. The Bangladesh batter said team success comes before personal milestones, stressing that consistent performances in the domestic arena could open the door to bigger opportunities. &amp;quot;I think first of all the Rajshahi team is more important to me than individual achievements,&amp;quot; Shanto said, adding that his focus is on making a regular impact,...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53475">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chattogram Royals owner asks BCB to take over franchise</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53444</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53444</guid>
      <description>Chattogram Royals owner Kayum Rashed has asked the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) to take over the operations of the franchise for the remainder of the Bangladesh Premier League season, BPL Governing Council member secretary Iftekhar Rahman Mithu told Daily Sun on Thursday. Kayum submitted a written request to the BCB, citing difficulties in continuing to run the team under the current circumstances, reports Daily Sun. “We have just received the letter. We will sit with the players and discuss t...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53444">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smith returns as Australia prepare an all-pace attack for Boxing Day test</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53466</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53466</guid>
      <description>Steve Smith returns to action in the Boxing Day test against England as Australia opted to include four fast bowlers in their 12-man squad, with spinner Todd Murphy, who was brought into the fold to replace Nathan Lyon, not finding a spot. Fast bowler Jhye Richardson, who has not played in the longest format since 2021, has been brought back after fine domestic form on his return from shoulder surgery. Brendan Doggett who played in the first two tests, and Michael Neser, who was part of the pink...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53466">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bashar, Nafees and Babul appointed as BCB takes charge of Royals</title>
      <link>https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53467</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53467</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has appointed former national captain Habibul Bashar as mentor, Mizanur Rahman Babul as head coach and Nafees Iqbal as team manager of the Chattogram Royals after agreeing to take over the franchise’s operations for the remainder of the Bangladesh Premier League season. The appointments follow franchise owner Kayum Rashed’s request to the BCB to assume control of the team, citing difficulties in continuing to run the side under the prevailing circumstances. BCB off...</description>
      <category>sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.bd-pratidin.com/sports/2025/12/25/53467">BD Pratidin</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>