<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BD News - BSS News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EhsanulHaqueSiam/BDNewsPaperScraper</link>
    <description>Latest news from Bangladeshi newspapers (5 articles)</description>
    <language>en-bd</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:57:17 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>BDNewsPaperScraper RSS Generator</generator>
    <item>
      <title>BNP to launch cleaning drive at July 36 Expressway (300-feet) tomorrow morning | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/345111</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/345111</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 25, 2025 (BSS) - Dhaka Metropolitan North unit of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) will conduct a voluntary clean-up drive tomorrow morning to remove waste generated following the massive public gathering held to mark the &amp;#x27;historic homecoming&amp;#x27; of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman. BNP Media Cell Convener Professor Dr. Moudud Hossain Alamgir Pavel disclosed the information to the media today. The cleaning operation will cover the July 36 Expressway (300-feet road), Airpor...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/345111">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:12 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Assistant for Home Affairs Khuda Baksh resigns | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/344956</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/344956</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 24, 2025 (BSS) - Chief Adviser&amp;#x27;s Special Assistant for Home Affairs Md Khuda Baksh Chowdhury has resigned from his post. The Cabinet Division issued a notification on Wednesday night, saying that the President has already accepted the resignation. &amp;quot;The resignation of Mr Khuda Baksh Chowdhury, the Special Assistant entrusted with executive authority with the rank of State Minister at the Ministry of Home Affairs of the interim government of the People&amp;#x27;s Republic of Banglades...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/344956">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique Rahman thanks countrymen for warm reception | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/345108</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/345108</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 25, 2025 (BSS) - BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman today expressed his sincere thanks and gratitude to the people of the country for the warm reception accorded to him upon his return home from London after long 17 years. A press release issued today said that following his arrival in the country from London, a massive gathering of people was seen stretching from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport to the expressway popularly known as the “300 Feet Road”. The historic a...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/345108">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Day today | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/344954</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/344954</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 25, 2025 (BSS) - Christmas Day, marking the birth anniversary of Jesus Christ, a Jewish preacher and religious leader of the first century, will be observed across the country on Thursday. Christian community in Bangladesh, like elsewhere in the world, will celebrate the day with religious fervour and festivity. Special prayers will be offered at churches, which will be illuminated for the occasion, while makeshift Christmas trees will be set up at homes, churches and missi...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/344954">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:07 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People&amp;#x27;s life, culture key to China-Bangladesh media exchange: Chinese envoy | News</title>
      <link>https://www.bssnews.net/news/344959</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bssnews.net/news/344959</guid>
      <description>News Flash DHAKA, Dec 24, 2025 (BSS) - Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen said that media exchange plays a vital role in understanding the civilization and culture of both countries. &amp;quot;Media exchange allows us to learn closely from each other. The foundation of China-Bangladesh media exchange is the life and culture of our peoples. This provides a strong base for building a relationship of justice between the two countries,&amp;quot; he said. The envoy made the remarks at a function titled &amp;#x27;Golden S...</description>
      <category>national</category>
      <source url="https://www.bssnews.net/news/344959">BSS News</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:58:05 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>