<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BD News - New Age</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EhsanulHaqueSiam/BDNewsPaperScraper</link>
    <description>Latest news from Bangladeshi newspapers (19 articles)</description>
    <language>en-bd</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:57:17 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>BDNewsPaperScraper RSS Generator</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Flight carrying Tarique Rahman lands at Dhaka airport</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286145/flight-carrying-tarique-rahman-lands-at-dhaka-airport</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286145/flight-carrying-tarique-rahman-lands-at-dhaka-airport</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chairman Tarique Rahman returned home from London on Thursday with his wife and daughter after his 17-year exile in London. A flight of Biman Bangladesh Airlines carrying them landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport via Sylhet in Dhaka at 11:40am. Earlier, the flight made a stopover at Sylhet&amp;#x27;s Osmani International Airport at about 9:58am.</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286145/flight-carrying-tarique-rahman-lands-at-dhaka-airport">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique calls chief adviser after landing at airport, expresses gratitude for security arrangements</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286149/tarique-calls-chief-adviser-after-landing-at-airport-expresses-gratitude-for-security-arrangements</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286149/tarique-calls-chief-adviser-after-landing-at-airport-expresses-gratitude-for-security-arrangements</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chair Tarique Rahman on Thursday expressed his gratitude to interim government chief adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus for the arrangements made, particularly for his security, on the occasion of his return from London. Soon after landing at the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka, Tarique Rahman made a phone call to the chief adviser from the airport lounge. A video of the conversation was later shared in Tarique’s verified Facebook page with the c...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286149/tarique-calls-chief-adviser-after-landing-at-airport-expresses-gratitude-for-security-arrangements">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only 27.24pc can influence govt decisions: final report</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286242/only-2724pc-can-influence-govt-decisions-final-report</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286242/only-2724pc-can-influence-govt-decisions-final-report</guid>
      <description>Only 27.24 per cent of citizens say they can influence government decisions at any level, according to the final report on the Citizen Perception Survey 2025. The figure, however, drops to 21.99 per cent when it comes specifically to political influence, said the report released by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics at a ceremony at the BBS auditorium in the capital Dhaka on Wednesday. The preliminary report on the survey was released in June. While the findings suggest a widespread sense of di...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286242/only-2724pc-can-influence-govt-decisions-final-report">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bulletproof bus arrives at airport ahead of Tarique Rahman’s return</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286144/bulletproof-bus-arrives-at-airport-ahead-of-tarique-rahmans-return</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286144/bulletproof-bus-arrives-at-airport-ahead-of-tarique-rahmans-return</guid>
      <description>A bulletproof bus arrived at the CIP gate of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Thursday morning amid tight security ahead of the return of Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chairman Tarique Rahman. The specially prepared bus, painted in red and green, bears large portraits of BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia, BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman and party founder Ziaur Rahman. It also displays slogans highlighting democracy and political struggle. The vehicle’s windows are reinforced, and sec...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286144/bulletproof-bus-arrives-at-airport-ahead-of-tarique-rahmans-return">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Youth beaten after being tied to electric pole in Chapainawabganj</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286241/youth-beaten-after-being-tied-to-electric-pole-in-chapainawabganj</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286241/youth-beaten-after-being-tied-to-electric-pole-in-chapainawabganj</guid>
      <description>A young man was beaten and stabbed to injuries after being tied to an electric pole at Shibganj upazila in Chapainawabganj on Wednesday evening, allegedly due to an internal feud. The incident took place at about 7:00pm in the Umorpur Ghat area of Shyampur union. The injured was Abu Sufian Siju, 25, son of Rabiul Islam of Shyampur–Bajitpur village under the upazila. According to the police and local residents, a group of local youth tied Siju to an electric pole and stabbed him with sharp weapon...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286241/youth-beaten-after-being-tied-to-electric-pole-in-chapainawabganj">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crude bomb explodes at Malibagh</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286239/crude-bomb-explodes-at-malibagh</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286239/crude-bomb-explodes-at-malibagh</guid>
      <description>A crude bomb was exploded near Malibagh intersection in the capital Dhaka on Thursday, a day after a youth was killed in a crude bomb explosion at Moghbazar on Wednesday. A case has been filed in connection with the murder of the youth, the police said. At Malibagh, the crude bomb was exploded at about 12:00pm, according to the Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s traffic division. No casualties were reported in the incident. Meanwhile, a firecracker-like object exploded next to the garbage depot at Mali...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/country/286239/crude-bomb-explodes-at-malibagh">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People’s life, culture key to China-Bangladesh media exchange: Chinese envoy</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/286240/peoples-life-culture-key-to-china-bangladesh-media-exchange-chinese-envoy</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/286240/peoples-life-culture-key-to-china-bangladesh-media-exchange-chinese-envoy</guid>
      <description>Chinese ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen has said that media exchange plays a vital role in understanding the civilisation and culture of both countries. ‘Media exchange allows us to learn closely from each other. The foundation of China-Bangladesh media exchange is the life and culture of our peoples. This provides a strong base for building a relationship of justice between the two countries,’ he said. The envoy made the remarks at a function titled Golden Silk Road Bangladesh Media Award held...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/foreign-affairs/286240/peoples-life-culture-key-to-china-bangladesh-media-exchange-chinese-envoy">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP activists crowding 300 Feet Road, adjacent places to welcome Tarique</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286143/bnp-activists-crowding-300-feet-road-adjacent-places-to-welcome-tarique</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286143/bnp-activists-crowding-300-feet-road-adjacent-places-to-welcome-tarique</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party leaders and activists started crowding the 300 Feet Road since Thursday morning to welcome its acting chairman Tarique Rahman’s homecoming after 17 years. Leaders and activists were joining the rally since Morning holding placards, photos of Tarique Rahman, fastoons and wearing T-shirts and caps. Kazi Khairuzzaman Shipon, BNP Bagherhat district vice-president, said that he reached Dhaka city two days ago and was staying at a hotel for attending the event. ‘We are her...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286143/bnp-activists-crowding-300-feet-road-adjacent-places-to-welcome-tarique">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nation ready to welcome Tarique Rahman in fascist free Bangladesh: Salahuddin</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286141/nation-ready-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-in-fascist-free-bangladesh-salahuddin</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286141/nation-ready-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-in-fascist-free-bangladesh-salahuddin</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed has said that the nation is ready to accord a grand reception to the party’s acting chairman Tarique Rahman in fascist free Bangladesh. ‘The fascist regime was toppled by a student-people uprising last year. We are very happy and pleased that the nation will welcome BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman in a fascist free Bangladesh,’ he said while briefing journalists in front of the VIP gate of the Hazrat Shahjalal Airport in ...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286141/nation-ready-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-in-fascist-free-bangladesh-salahuddin">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tight security at airport ahead of return of Tarique Rahman</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286142/tight-security-at-airport-ahead-of-return-of-tarique-rahman</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286142/tight-security-at-airport-ahead-of-return-of-tarique-rahman</guid>
      <description>Strict security measures have been put in place at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport ahead of the return of Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chairman Tarique Rahman. Several layers of security have been deployed around the VVIP terminal, with personnel from the army, BGB, air force, police and RAB on duty. RAB dog squads are conducting searches, while a special army unit has also been stationed in the area. In addition, the personal security force of the BNP chairperson and acting chairm...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286142/tight-security-at-airport-ahead-of-return-of-tarique-rahman">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique returns home today</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286115/tarique-returns-home-today</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286115/tarique-returns-home-today</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chairman Tarique Rahman is set to return to Dhaka on Thursday after more than 17 years in exile in the United Kingdom, marking a moment of major political significance. The homecoming has generated widespread anticipation nationwide, with supporters preparing to welcome him. The BNP has taken wide-ranging preparations, which party leaders say mirror both the significance of the moment and the sheer scale of public anticipation it has generated. They expressed ...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286115/tarique-returns-home-today">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCP seeks revision of nomination submission, withdrawal deadlines</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286119/ncp-seeks-revision-of-nomination-submission-withdrawal-deadlines</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286119/ncp-seeks-revision-of-nomination-submission-withdrawal-deadlines</guid>
      <description>The National Citizen Party on Wednesday expressed concern about the Election Commission’s capacity for holding the national polls on February 12 next year. The party urged the commission to reconsider the dates for submission of nomination papers and withdrawal of candidature, keeping the voting date unchanged. Speaking after a meeting between an NCP delegation and chief election commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin at the commission headquarters in Dhaka, NCP chief coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary said t...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286119/ncp-seeks-revision-of-nomination-submission-withdrawal-deadlines">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP names 10 more candidates, with nine for allies</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286057/bnp-names-10-more-candidates-with-nine-for-allies</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286057/bnp-names-10-more-candidates-with-nine-for-allies</guid>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party on Wednesday announced candidates for 10 more constituencies, sharing nine of the seats with its movement partners, for the upcoming Jatiya Sangsad elections scheduled for February 12 next year. BNP secretary general Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir announced the names of the 10 candidates at a press conference at the party’s chairperson’s office in the capital’s Gulshan area. Of the 10 candidates, Liberal Democratic Party secretary general Redwan Ahmed, who joined th...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/286057/bnp-names-10-more-candidates-with-nine-for-allies">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NDF sets candidates for 122 seats</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286032/ndf-sets-candidates-for-122-seats</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286032/ndf-sets-candidates-for-122-seats</guid>
      <description>The newly-formed National Democratic Front, led by Jatiya Party factions, announced the names of the candidates for 122 seats for the upcoming Jatiya Sangsad elections scheduled for February 12. The executive chairman of a JP faction, Mujibul Haque Chunnu, announced the names of aspirant candidates at a press conference at a city hotel on Tuesday. JP faction chairman Anisul Islam Mahmud, secretary general ABM Ruhul Amin Hawlader, Jatiya Party-JP chairman Anwar Hossain Manju and others spoke at t...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286032/ndf-sets-candidates-for-122-seats">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TARIQUE RETURN: Railway to run special trains, HSIA prohibits visitor entry from evening</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285982/tarique-return-railway-to-run-special-trains-hsia-prohibits-visitor-entry-from-evening</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285982/tarique-return-railway-to-run-special-trains-hsia-prohibits-visitor-entry-from-evening</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Railway is scheduled to start running special trains from today to carry Bangladesh Nationalist Party leaders and activists on the occasion of the party’s leader ’s homecoming tomorrow. Also, Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport authorities prohibited all visitors except designated passengers from entering its area for 24 hours starting from 6:00pm today citing special operational and security reasons. Biman Bangladesh Airlines authorities in a press also also requested the airport-...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285982/tarique-return-railway-to-run-special-trains-hsia-prohibits-visitor-entry-from-evening">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parties pledge democratic country thru reforms</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286026/parties-pledge-democratic-country-thru-reforms</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286026/parties-pledge-democratic-country-thru-reforms</guid>
      <description>Leaders of major political parties on Tuesday expressed grave concern, saying that the recent incidents of violence were casting uncertainty over the forthcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad election. They also outlined their respective visions for democratic reform, economic recovery and governance in post-uprising Bangladesh. The leaders at a dialogue also pledged to build a new Bangladesh through necessary reforms and obliterating fascism, and by means of leading the country to achieve economic freedo...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286026/parties-pledge-democratic-country-thru-reforms">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NCP likely to join Jamaat-led alliance</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286213/ncp-likely-to-join-jamaat-led-alliance</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286213/ncp-likely-to-join-jamaat-led-alliance</guid>
      <description>The National Citizen Party, formed by student and youth organisers of the July uprising in February this year, is likely to join the Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami-led alliance ahead of the next general election and the national referendum. The NCP is, however, in confusion about its involvement with the recently formed Ganatantrik Sanskar Jote, an NCP-led alliance launched on December 7. The components of the alliance are the NCP, the Bangladesh Rashtra Sanskar Andolan and the Amar Bangladesh Party...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286213/ncp-likely-to-join-jamaat-led-alliance">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP cedes 4 seats to Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285963/bnp-cedes-4-seats-to-jamiat-ulema-e-islam</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285963/bnp-cedes-4-seats-to-jamiat-ulema-e-islam</guid>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party allotted four Jatiya Sangsad constituencies to the Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam Bangladesh as part of an electoral understanding ahead of the 13th JS elections. As a result of the agreement, BNP electoral symbol ‘sheaf of paddy’ will not be used in these constituencies. Instead, voters were urged to cast their votes for the candidates contesting with the ‘date palm tree’ symbol. BNP secretary general Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir made the announcement at a press conference...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/Politics/285963/bnp-cedes-4-seats-to-jamiat-ulema-e-islam">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarique returns home to rolling reception</title>
      <link>https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286210/tarique-returns-home-to-rolling-reception</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286210/tarique-returns-home-to-rolling-reception</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party acting chair Tarique Rahman returned to the country on Thursday after ending 17 years in forced exile in the United Kingdom, marking his homecoming with a historic reception attended by over 10 lakh people. Tarique arrived at the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport at around 11:40am on a Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight from London. He was accompanied by his wife Zubaida Rahman, their daughter Zaima Rahman, and the family’s pet cat Zeebu. Extensive security measur...</description>
      <category>politics</category>
      <source url="https://www.newagebd.net/post/politics/286210/tarique-returns-home-to-rolling-reception">New Age</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>