<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BD News - Prothom Alo</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EhsanulHaqueSiam/BDNewsPaperScraper</link>
    <description>Latest news from Bangladeshi newspapers (50 articles)</description>
    <language>en-bd</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:57:17 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>BDNewsPaperScraper RSS Generator</generator>
    <item>
      <title>In pictures: Tarique Rahman returns home</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/81wakzxv9b</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/81wakzxv9b</guid>
      <description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has arrived in the country. The Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight carrying Tarique Rahman landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka at 11:39 am on Thursday. He was accompanied by his wife Zubaida Rahman and daughter Zaima Rahman. BNP leaders and activists later welcomed Tarique Rahman and his family at the airport.At 12:35 pm, Tarique Rahman exited through the VIP gate. Standing at the front of the bus, he waved to the leaders and activists and o...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/81wakzxv9b">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:17:12 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now is the best time for a leader to become a statesman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/rhv5c3tdah</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/rhv5c3tdah</guid>
      <description>One of our distinguished poets, Helal Hafiz, wrote an outstanding poem titled “Forbidden Editorial.” Two widely quoted lines from the poem are:&amp;quot;Now is the prime of youth; Now is the time to go to war.&amp;quot;For our country, this is very much a “time of struggle”—a struggle to bring the nation back onto the right path. We are lost in thought, wondering who will lead us in this “struggle.” No one seems particularly promising. At this critical moment, we need a statesman. If poet Helal Hafiz were still a...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/rhv5c3tdah">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:52:31 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Tarique Rahman’s return is important</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/6mjkntth90</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/6mjkntth90</guid>
      <description>Ahead of Cambodia’s 2013 general election, two political parties—the Human Rights Party and the Sam Rainsy Party (later renamed the Candlelight Party)—merged in 2012 to form the Cambodian National Rescue Party (CNRP). In the 2013 election, the CNRP mounted an unexpectedly strong challenge to the ruling Cambodian People’s Party led by authoritarian Prime Minister Hun Sen. Of the 123 seats in parliament, the ruling party won 68, while the CNRP secured 55.Following this outcome, the CNRP came under...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/6mjkntth90">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:11:11 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National consensus: Tarique Rahman’s vision of new politics</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/n5tp6znobi</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/n5tp6znobi</guid>
      <description>Tarique Rahman has observed that hostile relations between the political parties are a major barrier to national progress. In an exchange of opinion meeting with grassroots leaders and workers of the BNP on 31 August 2024, he made it clear that they would not take revenge for the repression they had undergone in the past 17 years.“We’ll establish rule of justice,” he said. To him, political changeover does not mean mere transfer of power but qualitative change in the state. Thus, he promised tha...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/n5tp6znobi">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:41:29 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP allocates 4 seats to Jamiat Ulama-e-Islam</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/305vuq2c2h</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/305vuq2c2h</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has allocated four parliamentary constituencies to its partner in the joint political movement, Jamiat Ulama-e-Islam Bangladesh, for the forthcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election.This information was disclosed today, Tuesday, at a press conference held at the BNP chairperson’s political office in Gulshan by the party’s secretary general, Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir.It was stated at the press conference that the four seats allocated by BNP to Jamiat Ulama...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/305vuq2c2h">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:48:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economy under the dark cloud of violent politics</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/9ajfdkjyu7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/9ajfdkjyu7</guid>
      <description>The recent wave of violence has created deep anxiety in public life. The day after the Bangladesh Election Commission announced the schedule for the national election, on 12 December, young political leader Sharif Osman Hadi was shot by assailants in broad daylight. He later died while undergoing treatment in Singapore. Hadi’s killing sends a stark message, that expressing dissent has now become dangerous.This is not confined to politics alone. Attacks on two leading newspapers and two cultural ...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/9ajfdkjyu7">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:21:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editors’ Council, NOAB jointly hold protest meeting, human chain</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/u5vpnd37w1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/u5vpnd37w1</guid>
      <description>The Editors’ Council, the organisation of newspaper editors, and the Newspaper Owners’ Association of Bangladesh (NOAB) jointly organised a protest meeting and human chain titled ‘Bangladesh under Mob Violence’ in Dhaka on Monday. Leaders of various political parties, professional bodies, business organisations, journalists’ organisations, and representatives of civil society from different walks of life came to express solidarity. After the protest meeting, a human chain was held on the road be...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/photo/bangladesh/u5vpnd37w1">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:49:30 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP leaves Brahmanbaria-2 to Jamiat; Rumeen, two other BNP leaders to contest as independents</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/7b38q2bbp0</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/7b38q2bbp0</guid>
      <description>Former reserved-seat lawmaker and BNP&amp;#x27;s international affairs assistant secretary Rumeen Farhana has not received the party nomination from the Brahmanbaria-2 constituency (Sarail–Ashuganj and parts of Bijoynagar). BNP has ceded the seat to Maulana Junayed Al Habib, vice president of the central committee of Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam Bangladesh.The information was disclosed on Tuesday at a press conference held at the BNP chairperson’s political office in Gulshan by the party’s Secretary General, Mir...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/7b38q2bbp0">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:19:08 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous conspiracy underway to obstruct transitional process: Mirza Fakhrul</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/pyqkxx8riy</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/pyqkxx8riy</guid>
      <description>Stating that Bangladesh is going through a “transitional process,” Mirza Fakhrul said, “Even now, it is apparent that certain individuals and quarters have undertaken a dangerous conspiracy to obstruct this transitional process.”Mirza Fakhrul made these remarks on Tuesday afternoon while addressing a press briefing at the BNP chairperson’s political office in Gulshan. Earlier, BNP held a meeting with leaders of Jamiat Ulema-e-Islam Bangladesh. He also announced that four seats would be allotted ...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/pyqkxx8riy">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:10:40 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despite ‘risks’, Asif Mahmud collects nomination form to contest election</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/qc5v42bap2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/qc5v42bap2</guid>
      <description>Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuiyan, who resigned from his position as an adviser, personally went to the local election office to collect a nomination form to contest the 13th parliamentary election from the Dhaka–10 constituency. The July uprising leader also stated that he is aware his personal safety is currently at risk.A former student of the University of Dhaka and a frontline leader of the July uprising as a coordinator of the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement, Asif Mahmud took the oath as an ...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/qc5v42bap2">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:53:51 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Had I resigned I wouldn’t be sitting here: Home Affairs Adviser</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/government/7ye3pj7vkl</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/government/7ye3pj7vkl</guid>
      <description>Responding to rumours about his resignation, Home Affairs Adviser Lieutenant General (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said, “If I had resigned, I would not be sitting here.”He made the comment at a press conference at the conference room of the Ministry of Home Affairs at the Secretariat on Monday, in response to a question from a journalist after the 18th meeting of the Advisory Council Committee on Law and Order.Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said that today’s meeting discussed overall security prep...</description>
      <category>government</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/government/7ye3pj7vkl">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:11:04 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 special trains allocated for leaders, activists attending Tarique Rahman’s reception</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/gh59tc0mwk</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/gh59tc0mwk</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Railway is set to operate 10 special trains to bring people to the programme organised to mark the return of BNP’s acting chairman Tarique Rahman to the country. Following BNP’s request, the railway will provide these special trains next Thursday in exchange for the fare. In addition, extra coaches will be added to regular trains for the convenience of those attending the rally.A press release from the Ministry of Railways announced the operation of these special trains. The railway w...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/gh59tc0mwk">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 22:00:50 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attacks on Prothom Alo, Daily Star, 2 cultural organisations: 31 suspects identified, 9 arrested</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/27gbd5rft9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/27gbd5rft9</guid>
      <description>Law enforcement agencies have arrested at least nine people in raids carried out across Dhaka and other parts of the country up to Monday morning in connection with attacks on the offices of the national dailies Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, as well as two cultural organisations, Chhayanaut and Udichi.The information was disclosed in a press release posted on the chief adviser’s verified Facebook page at 10:31 am today, Monday.Late on Thursday (18 December) night, assailants vandalised and loo...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/27gbd5rft9">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:01:45 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politicians seek security, gunmen to government</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/yhxd06zsdo</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/yhxd06zsdo</guid>
      <description>Several politicians have applied to the government seeking security. Some have requested a police team to provide protection. Others have asked for armed guards or gunmen. Some have applied for firearms licenses.Amid growing concern over the country’s law and order situation, such applications are being submitted to the Ministry of Home Affairs on behalf of politicians. Some have sought both security and firearms licenses at the same time.Sources at the Ministry of Home Affairs said that applica...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/yhxd06zsdo">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:28:56 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It was not just an attack on Prothom Alo-Daily Star, it is an attack on democracy: Mirza Fakhrul</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/9icpwtrdiz</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/9icpwtrdiz</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said that this is not only an attack on Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, it is an attack on democracy itself. So, he said all pro-democracy forces must unite to resist this evil force.Mirza Fakhrul made the remarks while expressing solidarity at a protest rally organised in response to the attacks and arson at the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, as well as the harassment of Nurul Kabir, editor of New A...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/9icpwtrdiz">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:20:30 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How BNP wants to build the country</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/0vfp9007kh</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/0vfp9007kh</guid>
      <description>Perhaps for the first time in Bangladesh’s history, a political party has arranged training for its own leaders and activists to ensure that its specific programmes reach everyone, from urban citizens to marginalised communities. From 7 to 13 December, BNP provided training on eight topics to leaders and activists from its affiliated organisations as well as the main party.The “Nation-Building Programme” functioned not only as a set of training workshops, but also, through these workshops, outli...</description>
      <category>Op-Ed</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/op-ed/0vfp9007kh">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:41:16 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BNP gets permission to hold reception for Tarique Rahman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/y7j6o96mm9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/y7j6o96mm9</guid>
      <description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has received permission from the Dhaka divisional commissioner to organise a reception marking the return home of its acting chairman, Tarique Rahman, reports BSS.The matter was confirmed Sunday night by BNP Media Cell member Shairul Kabir Khan. After spending 17 years in exile in London, UK, Tarique Rahman is set to return to Bangladesh on 25 December. Shairul Kabir Khan said the party has received written approval to organise the reception to mark the act...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/y7j6o96mm9">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:48:18 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nomination papers collected on behalf of Khaleda Zia and Tarique Rahman in Bogura</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/ldz0wa7lpx</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/ldz0wa7lpx</guid>
      <description>Ahead of the 13th national parliamentary election, nomination papers have been collected on behalf of BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia for the Bogura-7 (Gabtali–Shajahanpur) constituency, and on behalf of the party’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman for the Bogura-6 (Sadar) constituency.Around 1:30 pm today, Sunday, Khaleda Zia’s adviser and former MP Helaluzzaman Talukder collected the nomination papers on her behalf from the office of the district election officer in the Khandar area of the cit...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/ldz0wa7lpx">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:31:21 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some are trying to create anarchy in the country: Tarique Rahman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/local-news/spevbkbe5a</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/local-news/spevbkbe5a</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) acting chairman Tarique Rahman has warned party leaders and activists to remain vigilant, saying the days ahead will not be easy. Anarchy has begun in different parts of the country, and some are trying to create disorder. Everyone must stay alert, he said.Tarique Rahman made these remarks today, Sunday afternoon while speaking online as the chief guest at the inauguration of a digital memorial for the July martyrs at the Shaheed Titu Auditorium in Edward Park,...</description>
      <category>local news</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/local-news/spevbkbe5a">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:53:51 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overall law and order situation under control: EC</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/q6tql3lkg0</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/q6tql3lkg0</guid>
      <description>Despite concerns among political parties following the murder of potential candidate Sharif Osman Hadi, the Election Commission (EC) believes that the overall law and order situation in the country remains under control.Speaking to newspersons today, Sunday, after a meeting of the EC with the three service chiefs, Election Commissioner Brigadier General Abul Fazal Md Sanaullah (Retd.) said, “There are internal disputes within parties and conflicts among multiple parties. But overall, if we asses...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/q6tql3lkg0">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 21:38:54 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Country can&amp;#x27;t move forward amid so much division and crisis: Matiur Rahman</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/uy3h9c31il</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/uy3h9c31il</guid>
      <description>Prothom Alo Editor Matiur Rahman has said that creating an environment of national unity and reconciliation is now the most important task for Bangladesh.“No country can survive with so much conflict, so much division, and so many crises. Nor can any government effectively run a country under such conditions,” he said.Matiur Rahman made the remarks at a view exchange meeting organised on the occasion of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s “historic return to the homeland.”The meeting was held o...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/uy3h9c31il">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 20:18:22 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Mobocracy’ became rampant due to government weakness: Salahuddin Ahmed</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/6opa87arm4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/6opa87arm4</guid>
      <description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed has said that the attacks and arson on the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star have damaged Bangladesh’s image worldwide, blaming government weakness for allowing what he termed “mobocracy” to become rampant. He said such tendencies must be suppressed firmly.He made the remarks on Sunday afternoon at a discussion meeting with senior media figures, organised to mark BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s “historic homecoming day,” at the Radisson...</description>
      <category>Politics</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/politics/6opa87arm4">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:13:39 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police find no ‘credible’ evidence of sabotage</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/receev0w5v</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/receev0w5v</guid>
      <description>As of Sunday noon, no case has been filed at Lakshmipur Sadar police station in connection with a fire at the home of a BNP leader. Police say they have not found credible evidence that the incident resulted from sabotage. The fire service has expressed a similar view. However, the BNP leader claims that the door was locked from the outside, preventing him from escaping.The matter was disclosed in a press release signed on Saturday night by Hossain Mohammad Raihan Kazemi, additional superintende...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/receev0w5v">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:56:16 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New kind of ‘media environment’ is essential to build a new Bangladesh: Mahfuz Anam</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/2w4fagwg0o</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/2w4fagwg0o</guid>
      <description>Recalling the experience that no government in Bangladesh’s 53-year political history has truly accepted critical journalism, The Daily Star editor Mahfuz Anam has called for the acceptance of an independent and critical media in the new Bangladesh.He made the remarks at a discussion meeting organised on the occasion of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s “historic return home.” The meeting was held this afternoon (Sunday) at the Radisson Blu, with editors of daily newspapers and online news po...</description>
      <category>bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/2w4fagwg0o">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:56:32 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US univs seed start-ups</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/US-univs-seed-start-ups</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/US-univs-seed-start-ups</guid>
      <description>A decade ago, Devin Jameson might have chosen to drop out of college and work on Eversound, a wireless headset start-up for senior communities. Instead, Jameson was able to combine his co-founded company with his academic coursework through Cornell University’s eLab program, an accelerator curriculum he completed in 2015. The eLab program runs for a full academic year. Students build out their businesses while participating in lectures, class work, mentorship and receiving a $5,000 investment. A...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/US-univs-seed-start-ups">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 09:49:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>313,848 posts remain vacant under different ministries</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/313-848-posts-remain-vacant-at-different</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/313-848-posts-remain-vacant-at-different</guid>
      <description>State minister for public administration on Sunday told parliament that a total of 313,848 posts remain vacant under different ministries, reports UNB.In reply to a query from Jatiya Party MP Mujibul Haque Chunnu, the state minister said as many as 313,848 posts fell vacant at different ministries.The state minister also said some 290 government officials are currently serving as officers on special duty (OSD) while 177 officials and employees are working at different ministries and departments ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/313-848-posts-remain-vacant-at-different">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 20:55:56 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JU to host job fair Sunday</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/JU-to-organise-job-fair-Sunday</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/JU-to-organise-job-fair-Sunday</guid>
      <description>A job fair titled &amp;#x27;Career Boot Camp Campus Recruitment-2019&amp;#x27; will be held at Jahangirnagar University on Sunday.Jahangirnagar University Career Club (JUCC) is organising the fair at the seminar room of Zahir Raihan auditorium where Kazi IT Center will recruit fresh graduates from the university. JUCC president Hadi Siam made the disclosure at a press meet at Jahangirnagar University Journalists&amp;#x27; Association (JUJA) office on Saturday afternoon. &amp;quot;For the first time, we&amp;#x27;re going to introduce a mult...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/JU-to-organise-job-fair-Sunday">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 21:40:04 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BYLC awards winners of Youth Entrepreneurship Challenge</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BYLC-awards-winners-of-Youth-Entrepreneurship</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BYLC-awards-winners-of-Youth-Entrepreneurship</guid>
      <description>The winners of the Youth Entrepreneurship Challenge (YEC), a social initiative by Bangladesh Youth Leadership Center (BYLC) to encourage and promote the promising entrepreneurs, have been announced at a ceremony in the city, reports UNB. The YEC, an initiative under BYLC’s entrepreneurship development wing in association with DFID and Manusher Jonno Foundation, is part of the organisation’s efforts to nurture the passion of aspiring entrepreneurs with unique revenue-generating business ideas by ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BYLC-awards-winners-of-Youth-Entrepreneurship">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 17:58:45 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deepa Mehta finds reality cautionary, not scary</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Deepa-Mehta-finds-reality-cautionary-not-scary</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Deepa-Mehta-finds-reality-cautionary-not-scary</guid>
      <description>The dystopian world of Deepa Mehta&amp;#x27;s “Leila” is not a subliminal, but a blunt reminder of the world that could be in reality. An acclaimed filmmaker, whose brand of cinema has been fearless in confronting the harsh truths of the society, says showcasing reality is merely cautionary and not meant to be scary. &amp;quot;Leila&amp;quot;, adapted from Prayaag Akbar&amp;#x27;s eponymous novel, is a dark and ominous tale set in the fictional world of Aryavarta, where a leader&amp;#x27;s motto delves on &amp;#x27;peace by segregation&amp;#x27; and where c...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Deepa-Mehta-finds-reality-cautionary-not-scary">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 11:44:32 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Govt working to create 15m jobs in 5 years’</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/‘Govt-working-to-create-15m-jobs-in-5-years’</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/‘Govt-working-to-create-15m-jobs-in-5-years’</guid>
      <description>Prime minister and leader of the house Sheikh Hasina on Wednesday told the Jatiya Sangsad that her government has set a target of creating 15 million employments in the next five years. “Yes, it’s true that our government has set a goal of creating 15 million employments in the next five years,” she said in reply to a starred question from treasury bench member M Abdul Latif (Chattogram) during her question hour in the house. The prime minister said on the basis of the strategies and targets of ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/‘Govt-working-to-create-15m-jobs-in-5-years’">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 11:52:39 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singer Shahnaz Rahmatuallah dies</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Singer-Shahnaz-Rahmatuallah-dies</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Singer-Shahnaz-Rahmatuallah-dies</guid>
      <description>Celebrated singer Shahnaz Rahmatuallah died of heart attack on Saturday night. She was 65. Shahnaz breathed her last at her Baridhaara residence around 11:30pm after suffering a heart attack, dancer Doly Iqbal confirmed Prothom Alo. The singer left behind her husband, a son and a daughter and well-wishers to mourn. Shahnaz’s husband retired major Abul Bashar Rahmatullah said the namaaz-e-janaza of the singer will be held at Park Mosque near the road no. 9 of Baridhara residential area after the ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Singer-Shahnaz-Rahmatuallah-dies">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 08:56:20 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube, farming, cleaning jobs abroad rise as alternatives</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/YouTube-farming-cleaning-jobs-abroad-rise-as</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/YouTube-farming-cleaning-jobs-abroad-rise-as</guid>
      <description>Yoon Chang-hyun&amp;#x27;s parents told him to get his sanity checked when he quit his secure job as a researcher at Samsung Electronics Co in 2015 to start his own YouTube channel.The 65 million won ($57,619) a year salary - triple South Korea&amp;#x27;s average entry level wage - plus top-notch healthcare and other benefits offered by the world&amp;#x27;s biggest smartphone and memory chip maker was the envy of many college graduates.But burned out and disillusioned by repeated night shifts, narrowing opportunities for ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/YouTube-farming-cleaning-jobs-abroad-rise-as">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 20:35:18 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BREB to recruit 2000 line crews</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BREB-to-recruit-2000-line-crews</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BREB-to-recruit-2000-line-crews</guid>
      <description>BREB’s Palli Bidyut Samity will recruit some 2,000 line ‘crew level-1’.Bangladesh Rural Electrification Board (BREB) has published a circular in this regard, inviting the eligible candidates to apply for the posts.Eligibility: the applicants must have Secondary School Certificate (SSC) or equivalent exams degree with minimum CGPA of 2.5 (out of 5). Science background students will get priority. Applicants must be 18-22 years old on 1 April 2019. The age limit, however, is flexible up to 25 years...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/BREB-to-recruit-2000-line-crews">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 17:57:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&amp;#x27;Good men do bad things&amp;#x27;: Cheryl on #MeToo</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Good-men-do-bad-things-Cheryl-on-MeToo</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Good-men-do-bad-things-Cheryl-on-MeToo</guid>
      <description>Bestselling author Cheryl Strayed, whose memoir &amp;quot;Wild&amp;quot; was turned into an Oscar-nominated film about her recovery from trauma, says listening more is key to healing wounds between men and women in the age of #MeToo. Published in 2012, &amp;quot;Wild&amp;quot; -- which recounted Strayed&amp;#x27;s gruelling 1,100-mile solo hike along the Pacific Crest Trail in America at the age of 26 -- was a smash hit that prompted Oprah Winfrey to resurrect her book club. Two years later, the film starring Reese Witherspoon catapulted U...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Good-men-do-bad-things-Cheryl-on-MeToo">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 15:28:42 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curtain falls on Dhaka International Folk Fest Saturday</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Curtain-falls-on-Dhaka-International-Folk-Fest</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Curtain-falls-on-Dhaka-International-Folk-Fest</guid>
      <description>Las Migas from Spain and Shafqat Amanat Ali from Pakistan are scheduled to come to this bustling city to celebrate the spirit of folk music on the final day of the Dhaka International Folk Fest on Saturday. Baul Kabir Shah, Arnob, Nakshikatha, Swarobanjo and Bhabna Nritya Dol of the host country will also be performing on the third day, reports UNB. DIKANDA from Poland, Wadali Brothers and Satyaki Banerjee from India and Abdul Hai Dewan from Bangladesh performed on the first day of the three-day...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Curtain-falls-on-Dhaka-International-Folk-Fest">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 11:12:48 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mrinal Sen no more</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Filmmaker-Mrinal-Sen-passes-away</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Filmmaker-Mrinal-Sen-passes-away</guid>
      <description>Mrinal Sen, legendary filmmaker of Indian cinema based in West Bengal, is no more. Sen died of a cardiac arrest at his residence in Kolkata&amp;#x27;s Bhabanipur on Sunday, according to UNB. He was 95. Tracing his roots to Faridpur in Bangladesh, Sen was born on 14 May, 1923. He has directed a handful of critically acclaimed films that put Bangla cinema on the map including &amp;quot;Baishe Srabon&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Chorus&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Akaler Sandhaney&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Bhuvan Shome&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Parasuram&amp;quot; and more. His fanbase, not surprisingly, spanned both in ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Filmmaker-Mrinal-Sen-passes-away">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 19:34:42 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portal to provide job services to unemployed youths</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Portal-to-provide-job-services-to-unemployed</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Portal-to-provide-job-services-to-unemployed</guid>
      <description>Kolorob Jobs, a digital job portal to create job opportunities for unemployed and vulnerable youths, was launched in the city on Sunday, reports UNB. The website is a project of Save the Children in Bangladesh. The aim of the platform is to make job placement easier for unemployed and vulnerable youth jobseekers in Bangladesh, said Mark Taylor Pierce, country director of Save the Children. He added that employers can recruit qualified semi-skilled and skilled workers for blue collar jobs using t...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Portal-to-provide-job-services-to-unemployed">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 12:20:34 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rock inspiration for the young</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Rock-inspiration-for-the-young</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Rock-inspiration-for-the-young</guid>
      <description>“We need to take care of young talent. Please take care of young talents - guitarists, drummers or keyboardists, whoever he or she is,” said Bangladesh&amp;#x27;s rock legend Ayub Bachchu, appealing to the people on behalf of up-and-coming musicians in a TV interview. Bachchu unexpectedly passed away on Thursday. Having gone through hardships at the beginning of his career, the multi-talented singer and songwriter wanted to ensure young talent across the country got the support they need. “This world is ...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Rock-inspiration-for-the-young">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 15:21:15 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selim Al Deen festivals begin at Shilpakala Academy</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Selim-Al-Deen-festivals-begin-at-Shilpakala</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Selim-Al-Deen-festivals-begin-at-Shilpakala</guid>
      <description>Marking the 69th birth anniversary of Natyacharya Selim Al Deen, two separate festivals began on the premises of Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy (BSA) in the capital on Friday, says UNB.Two theatre troops--Dhaka Theater and Swapnadal--separately organised the events marking the birth anniversary of the veteran artisan.As a part of the celebration, Swapnadal organised a discussion event on Friday at the Studio Theatre Hall of BSA while theatre personality Ataur Rahman was present as chief guest.Dir...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Selim-Al-Deen-festivals-begin-at-Shilpakala">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 10:18:09 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of any artwork is subjective: Sujoy Ghosh</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Evaluation-of-any-artwork-is-subjective-Sujoy</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Evaluation-of-any-artwork-is-subjective-Sujoy</guid>
      <description>India’s national award-winning filmmaker Sujoy Ghosh says engaging an audience must be the priority for any artwork, and the technicalities come later.The &amp;quot;Kahaani&amp;quot; director is in support of a short films award -- Critics Choice Short Film Awards (CCSFA) -- constituted by the Film Critics Guild&amp;#x27;s. Ghosh believes critics&amp;#x27; opinion on films are personal and subjective, whereas for the viewer, engagement is paramount.Asked about how he sets the parameters for critical analysis of a movie, Ghosh told...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Evaluation-of-any-artwork-is-subjective-Sujoy">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 17:52:18 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Library goers increase but not book lovers</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Library-goers-increase-but-not-book-lovers</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Library-goers-increase-but-not-book-lovers</guid>
      <description>Increasing number of young people visit these days libraries run by the government, despite apparent decline in the habit of reading books, according to users and authorities. Most of those seen in the libraries in recent times are actually candidates of Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) examinations, who use quiet atmosphere of the libraries for taking preparations. The increased presence of readers at libraries is understood by the rise in membership application in recent years, library authoriti...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Library-goers-increase-but-not-book-lovers">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 12:27:23 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dance star Akram Khan returns with last solo show</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Dance-star-Akram-Khan-returns-with-last-solo-show</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Dance-star-Akram-Khan-returns-with-last-solo-show</guid>
      <description>Britain&amp;#x27;s best-known choreographer Akram Khan has drawn on his roots for the final solo dance performance of his career, with a show that pays tribute to Indian soldiers who fought in World War I. &amp;quot;Xenos&amp;quot; -- which means stranger in Greek -- opens with two musicians on stage, playing an interpretation of Indian music in a festive atmosphere. Dressed for a performance, a dancer arrives, stumbling. The lights flicker, the music stalls and the dancer, a former soldier, is overcome by memories of war...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Dance-star-Akram-Khan-returns-with-last-solo-show">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 11:39:03 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overseas jobs panacea for youth unemployment?</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Overseas-jobs-panacea-for-youth-unemployment</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Overseas-jobs-panacea-for-youth-unemployment</guid>
      <description>Absorbing all unemployed youth into the job market is a daunting task that is not unique for Bangladesh. As nations observe the World Youth Skills Day Monday (July 15), what Bangladesh needs to do is instil skills into young, working-age people, making them market-ready for overseas jobs. The United Nations recognises rising youth unemployment as one of the most significant problems of developed and developing countries. Some 475 million new jobs need to be created over the next decade to absorb...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Overseas-jobs-panacea-for-youth-unemployment">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 12:14:08 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustafizur elated to be part of KKR in IPL</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/k4wo6ft78m</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/k4wo6ft78m</guid>
      <description>Bangladesh pacer Mustafizur Rahman was ecstatic to be part of Kolkata Knight Riders (KKR) for the first time in his Indian Premier League (IPL) career.&amp;quot;Hello KKR fans. I am Mustafizur Rahman. I am very happy and excited to be a part of the KKR team. See you soon,&amp;quot; Mustafizur said through a video message posted in KKR&amp;#x27;s social media handle.KKR secured Mustafizur&amp;#x27;s services for a whopping INR 92 million, making him the highest-paid Bangladeshi player in IPL history at the mini auction, held in Abu...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/k4wo6ft78m">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:37:12 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia all out for 371 in 3rd Ashes Test</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/kogzmbczny</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/kogzmbczny</guid>
      <description>Australia added a valuable 45 runs for their remaining two first innings wickets on day two of the third Ashes Test Thursday before being dismissed by England for 371.The hosts resumed on 326-8 with Mitchell Starc not out 33 and Nathan Lyon yet to score with temperatures soaring towards a forecast 39 Celsius at Adelaide Oval.Starc plundered five quick boundaries before being bowled by Jofra Archer for 54. Lyon and Scott Boland then piled on more misery for the tourists in a 23-run last-wicket st...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/kogzmbczny">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:05:48 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quota protesters stage demo demanding gazette</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Quota-protesters-stage-demo-demanding-gazette</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Quota-protesters-stage-demo-demanding-gazette</guid>
      <description>Quota protesters on Sunday staged a two-hour demonstration in colleges and universities across the country demanding immediate issuance of gazette notification abolishing quota system in public services. Agitated students began observing their strike around 11:00am by suspending classes and examinations, reports UNB. The demonstrators hold a human chain on Dhaka University campus demanding the issuance of gazette notification as per the announcement made by prime minister Sheikh Hasina in parlia...</description>
      <category>Business</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/youth/Quota-protesters-stage-demo-demanding-gazette">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 13:43:40 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&amp;#x27;Golden moment&amp;#x27; as Messi meets Tendulkar on India tour</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/yg0chtianf</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/yg0chtianf</guid>
      <description>Football icon Lionel Messi&amp;#x27;s second day in India passed smoothly Sunday, after a chaotic opening to his three-day tour, as the World Cup winner kicked balls into the crowd and met cricket legend Sachin Tendulkar.Messi greeted excited fans decked out in Argentina football jerseys at a packed Wankhede stadium in India&amp;#x27;s financial hub Mumbai, as supporters chanted his name.The 38-year-old Argentina and Inter Miami superstar took centre stage in the presence of India&amp;#x27;s sporting royalty including Ten...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/yg0chtianf">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:51:05 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khawaja makes the most of late lifeline as Australia reach 194 for 5</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/5mo1p106dr</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/5mo1p106dr</guid>
      <description>Usman Khawaja hit a defiant 82 Wednesday after being thrown a lifeline at the third Ashes Test in Adelaide as England fought hard in searing heat to stay in the contest at tea on day one.Batting after captain Pat Cummins won the toss as temperatures topped 36 Celsius, the hosts were 194-5 after the shock news of Steve Smith being ruled out with illness.At the break, Alex Carey was not out 48 and Josh Inglis on five.Smith, who has more than 10,000 runs, had been feeling unwell in the lead-up but ...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/5mo1p106dr">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:36:08 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSG ordered to pay around 60m euros to Mbappe in wage dispute</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/abdzdly81d</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/abdzdly81d</guid>
      <description>Paris Saint-Germain were ordered by a French labour court to pay their former forward Kylian Mbappe up to 61 million euros ($71.8 million) in unpaid wages and bonuses on Tuesday.France captain Mbappe, who left PSG in June 2024 to join Real Madrid, had been claiming over 260 million euros in total from his former club.PSG in turn had demanded Mbappe pay them 440 million euros.Mbappe, 26, also claimed the Qatari-owned reigning European champions had applied the wrong French legal classification to...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/football/abdzdly81d">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:46:50 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abrar powers Bangladesh to victory in U19 Asia Cup opener</title>
      <link>https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gvv1zkkaia</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gvv1zkkaia</guid>
      <description>Opener Jawad Abarar hit a brilliant 96-run knock as Bangladesh Under-19 team made a winning start to the Under-19 Asia Cup with a three-wicket victory over Afghanistan at ICC Cricket Stadium in Dubai today.Electing to bat first, Afghanistan youngsters posted a respectable 283-7, riding on a fluent century of Faisal Shinozada, who hammered a 94 ball-103, featuring eight fours and four sixes.Abarar whose innings included nine fours and six sixes was instrumental in chasing the challenging total as...</description>
      <category>Sports</category>
      <source url="https://en.prothomalo.com/sports/cricket/gvv1zkkaia">Prothom Alo</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 21:46:04 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>