<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>BD News - The Bangladesh Today</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EhsanulHaqueSiam/BDNewsPaperScraper</link>
    <description>Latest news from Bangladeshi newspapers (5 articles)</description>
    <language>en-bd</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:57:17 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>BDNewsPaperScraper RSS Generator</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka rejects Indian advice on election process: Touhid</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31619</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31619</guid>
      <description>Foreign Adviser Md Touhid Hossain today said Dhaka does not seek advice from India on Bangladesh’s election process, calling New Delhi’s recent comments unacceptable while reaffirming the interim government’s commitment to holding a free, fair and credible national election. “We do not want advice from our neighbours on how elections in Bangladesh should be held,” he said while responding to journalists’ questions at the Foreign Ministry here this afternoon. The adviser added that India had rema...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31619">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia wants Dhaka-Delhi to reduce tension</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31696</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31696</guid>
      <description>Russian Ambassador Alexander Grigoryevich Khozin today urged Bangladesh and India to reduce domestic tensions between the neighbouring countries. Speaking at a press briefing at the Embassy of the Russian Federation in Dhaka, the Ambassador underscored the importance of de-escalating tensions with India &amp;quot;the sooner the better,&amp;quot; while stressing that Russia does not interfere in bilateral relations between the two countries. He said bilateral relations between neighbouring countries should be guid...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31696">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid postal voting system to set global example: CEC</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31699</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31699</guid>
      <description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) A M M Nasir Uddin has said Bangladesh’s newly introduced ‘hybrid postal voting’ is expected to become a model for countries around the world. He made the remarks while talking to journalists after inspecting postal ballot operations at the Tejgaon Mail Processing Centre in the capital this afternoon. “We are hopeful that this hybrid model (online registration combine manual counting of postal ballots) will emerge as a global example,” the CEC said. He said that ...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31699">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamas official says Egypt to host Palestinian conference on Gaza future</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=30349</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=30349</guid>
      <description>A senior Hamas official said Saturday that Egypt would organise a conference for Palestinian factions to decide on the post-war future of the Gaza Strip, after the group accepted to release hostages under a US ceasefire plan. Egypt will host an &amp;quot;intra-Palestinian dialogue on Palestinian unity and the future of Gaza, including the administration of the Gaza Strip&amp;quot;, the official told AFP. Hamas on Friday said it would release hostages held in Gaza under US President Donald Trump&amp;#x27;s ceasefire plan, ...</description>
      <category>International</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=30349">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highest security for Tarique Rahman&amp;#x27;s homecoming on Dec 25: Home Adviser</title>
      <link>https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31693</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31693</guid>
      <description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has said the highest level of security will be ensured for the homecoming of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on December 25. &amp;quot;Maximum security measures have already been taken to ensure the safe arrival of Tarique Rahman in the country,&amp;quot; he said. The Home Adviser made the remarks today while briefing reporters after the 18th meeting of the Advisory Council Committee on Law and Order and on securit...</description>
      <category>Bangladesh</category>
      <source url="https://thebangladeshtoday.com/?p=31693">The Bangladesh Today</source>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>